本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P.
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福
This is Developing iOS Application, Winter of 2017.
这是iOS的应用，2017年的冬天。
CS193P 课程，iOS 应用程序开发
CS193P课程,iOS应用程序开发
And the only topic for today is a big one, Core Data,
今天唯一的主题是，Core Data，
which is an object oriented database.
这是一个面向对象的数据库。
But before I dive into this,
在我深入这个问题之前，
I'm actually going to revisit that demo we did last time
我将重新回顾上次我们做的那个demo
just briefly, because we ran out of time and so
简单来说，因为时间不够了
I wasn't able to show you the refresh control.
我不能给你展示刷新控制。
Now I posted the code for it, so
现在我发布了代码
I'm not gonna type all the code in here.
我不会在这里键入所有代码。
But I'm just gonna briefly show you
但我只是简单地告诉你们
how that refresh control worked, okay?
刷新控制是如何起作用的?
Okay, so we missed that.
好吧，我们错过了。
So here is the app we had from last time.
这是我们上次的应用。
By the way, I have modified our app
顺便说一下，我已经修改了我们的应用程序
here to change our request a little bit.
这里要稍微改变一下我们的要求。
If you remember this line of code from last time,
如果你还记得上次的代码，
it used to just have the query.
它过去只有查询。
But I've changed it to also filter out retweets and
但我改变了它，也过滤了retweets和
I've also put on the safe filter, which hopefully will
我也加入了安全滤镜，但愿如此
make it so that when I do these look ups,
当我做这些的时候，
these sort of up looks, we don't get stuff on the screen,
这些看起来，我们没有在屏幕上看到东西，
you know this is a family show,
你知道这是一个家庭表演，
so we don't want to see some of that stuff.
所以我们不想看到这些东西。
Anyway, hopefully, that'll work.
无论如何,希望这将工作。
So let's go back here and
我们回到这里
take a look at what this looks like.
看看这是什么样子。
There's my simulator right here.
这是我的模拟器。
So let's go ahead and search.
我们继续搜索。
Let's try Trump again and cross our fingers, all right.
让我们再试试特朗普，交叉手指，好吧。
So that's not, I don't see anything too terrible there.
那不是，我在那里没有看到任何可怕的东西。
Okay so what we added was this UI where we can pull down.
我们添加的是这个UI，我们可以把它拉下来。
Okay and it adds more tweets,
它添加了更多的推文，
you see how it added a tweet there?
你知道它是如何在那里添加一条tweet的吗?
We have the second pull right there,
我们有第二个拉力，
this was with the first pull.
这是第一次。
And we pull down again, no tweets this time, okay?
我们再次向下拉，这次没有推文，好吗?
So each time we pull down it's doing another twitter
所以每次我们拉下它，它都在做另一个twitter
fetch, and
取回,
may get more tweets depending if people are tweeting or not.
可能会得到更多的推文，这取决于人们是否在推特。
So let's take a look at the code to do this, again,
让我们再看一遍代码，
I posted this code, but
我发布了这个代码，但是
we'll just look at it, I'm not gonna type it all in,
我们来看看，我不会全部输入，
we're just gonna look at it real quick.
我们很快地看一下。
First of all, let's talk about how do I get this UI where
首先，我们来讨论一下如何得到这个UI
we pull down and it calls a method, or whatever?
我们向下拉，它调用一个方法，或者其他什么?
So let's go to look in our storyboard.
我们来看看故事板。
All right, so here's our storyboard, and
好的，这是我们的故事板
what I did was I just selected my table view controller and
我所做的就是选择了我的表视图控制器
I went down here to this refreshing.
我到这里来，让人耳目一新。
You see that refreshing choice?
你看到那个令人耳目一新的选择了吗?
And I changed it from disabled to enabled, and when I set it
我将它从禁用状态改为启用，当我设置它的时候
to enabled nothing changed here in the UI.
在UI中没有启用任何更改。
You can't see any spinning thing, but
你看不到任何旋转的东西，但是
over here in the document outline it created this
在文档大纲中，它创建了这个
refresh control right here.
刷新控制。
And so I can control drag from the document outline just as I
我可以从文档大纲中control拖动
can through here.
可以在这里通过。
So all I did to make this work is I just brought up
所以我所做的一切就是我刚刚提出的
my controller right here.
我的控制器。
And here's the method I did it with right here.
这是我在这里做的方法。
I just Ctrl dragged from the Refresh Control to this method
我只是从刷新控制中拖拽到这个方法
called refresh, okay?
称为刷新?
That's all I did to, to make that happen.
这就是我所做的一切，让这一切发生。
And inside refresh,
在刷新,
I just called that same method I had before, searchForTweets.
我刚才调用了同样的方法，searchForTweets。
This one right here, the one that search for tweets.
这个在这里，搜索推文的那个。
And that used to look like this,
以前是这样的，
I only changed one thing in here.
我在这里只改变了一件事。
It used to just get the twitterRequest by
它过去只是得到了twitterRequest
looking at our search term up here.
看这里的搜索项。
Remember this function?
还记得这个函数吗?
And all I did was added this, which says, if
我所做的就是加上这个，如果
the lastTwitterRequest has a newer version, then use that.
lastTwitterRequest有一个新版本，然后使用它。
But if it doesn't, then default back to doing to query
但如果它没有，则默认返回执行查询
request the way we used to.
请求我们过去的方式。
The only other things that I had to do was turn the refresh
我唯一要做的其他事情就是刷新
control off, you do that with the end refreshing.
控制，你这样做最后让人耳目一新。
So I just did that when I went back to the main queue here,
所以当我回到主队列时，
to get my results, so I turned it off.
为了得到结果，我关掉了它。
I also turned it off if for
我也把它关掉了
some reason I couldn't get any request or whatsoever.
我无法得到任何请求。
Okay, there's nothing in the search term field and
在搜索项字段中没有
I couldn't get a newer version of my last request.
我无法得到我最后一个请求的新版本。
So I just said, I'm gonna make sure that thing is not
所以我只是说，我要确保那个东西不是
spinning and spinning forever.
旋转,旋转,直到永远。
They wanna get out of here with that.
他们想要离开这里。
And the only other thing I had to do was up here,
我唯一要做的就是在这里，
when the search text changes, someone types#Stanford or
当搜索文本发生变化时，就会有人键入# Stanford或
something like that, I need to invalidate that last Twitter
像这样，我需要让最后的Twitter失效
request so that it's not trying to get new versions
请求，这样它就不会尝试获得新的版本
of the previous one that I had.
我之前说过的。
I want it to do the new one.
我想让它做新的。
And the way that I made it so that we had these little
我做这些的方法就是我们有这些小的
titles right here, see these titles two, three, four, five?
这里的标题，看这些标题2,3,4,5 ?
I implemented another UI table view data source method,
我实现了另一个UI表视图数据源方法，
this one down here.
下面这一个。
Called titleForHeaderInSection.
叫titleForHeaderInSection。
I just put titles on the sections.
我只是把标题写在了章节上。
Remember, each section is another pull from Twitter.
记住，每一节都是推特的另一项内容。
And so I just have each title.
所以我只有一个标题。
It's actually gonna be the count of things I had minus
它实际上是我得到的数减去的数
the section number.
部分号码。
So the top one is section zero.
最上面的是section 0。
So section zero is gonna show
所以section 0会显示出来
the number of pulls that I've made.
我做的抽拉次数。
tweets.count is how many pulls I made.
tweet。数是我赚了多少钱。
And it's obviously gonna
这显然会
decrement as the sections go down.
当截面下降时，减量。
Okay, so that's what gave us this.
这就是我们得到的结果。
And you can see that the longer we wait,
你可以看到，我们等待的时间越长，
obviously it pulls more information,
很明显，它能获取更多信息，
as tweets pile up.
因为微博也应接不暇了。
Okay, let's go back to our slides.
好的，我们回到幻灯片。
All right, here we go.
好了，开始吧。
So Core Data is this big framework inside of iOS for
Core Data是iOS内部的一个大框架
doing object-oriented databases.
做面向对象数据库。
So let's talk a little bit about what that means.
让我们稍微谈一下这意味着什么。
So, when do you need a database?
那么，什么时候需要数据库呢?
Well you need a database when you have a large amount of
当你有大量的时候你需要一个数据库
data, and especially if you want to kind of make queries
数据，特别是如果你想查询
into that data and find out things about that data and
输入数据并找出有关数据的信息
the relationships between all the things in there.
所有事物之间的关系。
You really can't do that by like,
你真的不能那样做，
taking a big dictionary or a big array and
拿一本大字典或大数组
searching through it, you need a database.
通过搜索，您需要一个数据库。
And so there's a lot of technologies for databases out
所以有很多关于数据库的技术
there but most of them are not object-oriented.
但大多数都不是面向对象的。
So we have this framework that Apple provides called
我们有一个苹果提供的框架
Core Data, it's what we call an object-oriented database
Core Data，我们称之为面向对象的数据库
but actually, it's really not an object-oriented database
但实际上，它并不是面向对象的数据库
on the inside.
在内部。
It's only an object-oriented database on the outside.
它只是一个面向对象的数据库。
The side that you look at.
你看到的那一边。
Underneath, it's actually a relational database usually.
在下面，它通常是一个关系数据库。
Now Core Data is designed to have any backend of storage.
现在Core Data被设计成具有任何后端存储。
But it's primary implementation is on top of
但它的主要实现是在上面
SQL which is a relational database.
是一个关系数据库。
How many people know what SQL Database is?
有多少人知道SQL数据库是什么?
Okay, almost all of you, good.
好了，几乎所有人都很好。
So, if we had to do databases in our iOS apps using SQL,
如果我们在iOS应用中使用SQL做数据库，
we'd be like no, I have to learn this whole query
我们会像不一样，我必须学习整个查询
language, and how am I gonna do this?
语言，我该怎么做呢?
Not to worry, we don't have to know any SQL to use core Data.
不用担心，我们不需要知道任何SQL来使用core Data。
No SQL whatsoever- we're just gonna purely do this
没有SQL，我们只需要这样做
on the object side.
在对象方面。
So how does this work?
那么它是如何工作的呢?
How does core Data work?
core Data是如何工作的?
Well, first we're gonna create a visual mapping
首先，我们要创建一个可视映射
between things in our database and
在我们的数据库和
some objects that we're gonna be able to program with
一些我们可以编程的对象
in our object-oriented code that we like.
在我们喜欢的面向对象代码中。
And kinda roughly, it's
有点粗略,它
the tables in the database are kinda gonna be objects.
数据库中的表有点像对象。
And the columns in the tables are kind of vars.
表格中的列是vars。
But we don't even really care what it's doing there.
但我们甚至不关心它在那里做什么。
What we're gonna focus on is this visual map,
我们要关注的是这个可视地图，
this visual description basically of our schema.
这个视觉描述基本上就是我们的模式。
Okay, how many people know what the word schema means?
有多少人知道图式是什么意思?
Okay, so two-thirds of you.
好的，三分之二的人。
So schema is basically the description of what's
图式基本上就是对事物的描述
in your database, not the contents of it but how all its
在你的数据库中，不是它的内容，而是它的全部
data types are and how they relate to each other, etc.
数据类型是和它们如何相互关联的，等等。
So we're gonna do all that graphically.
我们要用图形来做。
And this is what it looks like.
这就是它的样子。
First, if I wanna use Core Data in my app,
首先，如果我想在app中使用Core Data，
I'm almost certainly going to wanna click this button
我几乎肯定会想要点击这个按钮
that says Use Core Data.
这就是说使用核心数据。
We've seen it every time we've created an app, and we haven't
每次我们创建一个应用程序，我们都见过它
clicked it so far, but now we are going to click it.
到目前为止，点击它，但现在我们要点击它。
And clicking Use Core Data there,
点击使用Core Data，
is gonna create two things for us, this visual map,
为我们创建了两个东西，这个可视映射，
and some code in your App Delegate.
以及App委托中的一些代码。
And I'm gonna talk about both of those things.
我要谈谈这两件事。
Now before I go to the next slide,
在下一张幻灯片之前，
notice that the name of this app is CoreDataExample.
请注意，此应用程序的名称为CoreDataExample。
That's the, just the name of the app that I typed in there.
这就是我在这里输入的应用程序的名字。
So when I create this app, clicking that
当我创建这个应用时，点击它
Use Core Data on, you'll see that it created this file,
使用Core Data，你会看到它创建了这个文件，
CoreDataExample.xcdatamodeld.
CoreDataExample.xcdatamodeld。
So it chose the name of my app as it.
所以它选择了我的app的名字。
And this is going to be our data model, all right?
这将是我们的数据模型?
And so we'll, we'll talk about the AppDelegate
我们会讲到AppDelegate
code that Use Core Data also generated a little bit later.
使用核心数据的代码也会在稍后生成。
Right now we're gonna focus on this data model file.
现在我们关注这个数据模型文件。
All right, but before we even do that, what happens if we
好的，但在我们做之前，如果我们
have an existing app and you did not click Use Core Data?
有一个现有的应用程序，你没有点击使用Core Data吗?
And now you decided, hey, I wanna add core data.
现在你决定，嘿，我想添加core data。
Like maybe Smashtag Assignment 5 comes out and
比如Smashtag任务5出来了
I tell you to add some Core Data to Smashtag.
我告诉您添加一些Core Data到Smashtag。
And you're like, woh, I can't go back and
你说，哇，我不能回去了
click Use Core Data, it's too late.
点击使用Core Data，太晚了。
So you're gonna have to create this data model file
你需要创建这个数据模型文件
using new file.
使用新文件。
So you just go to File > New > File like this.
你只需要像这样打开>新的>文件。
You're not gonna pick any of
你不会选择任何一个
the things we've picked so far.
到目前为止我们所选的东西。
You're gonna scroll down to the section that
你要向下滚动到那部分
says Core Data.
核心数据表示。
And inside there these, there's two things,
在这里面，有两件事，
Data Model and Mapping Model.
数据模型和映射模型。
And make sure you pick Data Model because that's what you
确保你选择了数据模型，因为那就是你
want to do here is create your data model,
这里要做的是创建数据模型，
your schema essentially, for your database.
对于数据库，您的模式本质上是这样的。
It's gonna ask you what you wanna call it.
它会问你想叫什么。
Now, you don't have to call this the same as the name of
现在，你不必把这个叫做
your application like Use Core Data button does.
你的应用就像使用Core Data按钮一样。
You can call it anything you want.
你可以叫它任何你想要的东西。
So here, just to be different, I've called it Model,
这里，为了不一样，我把它叫做模型，
it's my model.
这是我的模型。
And by the way,
顺便说一下,
your core data is usually the model of a lot of MVCs.
您的核心数据通常是许多mvc的模型。
Okay, a lot of MVCs, their job is going to be to display
很多mvc，它们的任务就是显示
the data in the database, and so this data model is actually
数据库中的数据，实际上是这个数据模型
the MVC model as well for a lot of MVCs.
MVC模型也适用于许多MVC。
So I'll call this one model, and
我把这个叫做模型
you can see it created model.xedatamodeld.
您可以看到它创建了model . xedatamodeld。
So whether you get that file by doing Use Core Data or
所以不管你是通过使用Core Data获取这个文件
whether you get it by creating it yourself,
不管你是通过自己创造，
you're gonna have this mapping file.
你会有这个映射文件。
Now, let me go back to that AppDelegate thing.
现在，让我回到那个AppDelegate的事情。
I said they was gonna put some code in your AppDelegate.
我说过他们会在你的应用程序中添加一些代码。
It's very small amount of code.
这是非常小的代码。
But I wanted to show it to you right here.
但我想在这里展示给你们看。
This is what it looks like.
这就是它的样子。
It just creates this one var right here.
它只会在这里创建一个var。
By the way, if you didn't do Use Core Data, of course,
顺便说一下，如果你没有使用Core Data，当然，
you need this code in your AppDelegate,
在AppDelegate中需要这个代码，
how are you gonna get it?
你将如何得到它?
Just go create some dummy application.
只需要创建一些虚拟应用程序。
Call it Foo, it doesn't really matter what you call it.
把它叫做Foo，它并不重要。
Click Use Core Data when you create it and
创建时单击使用核心数据
then copy this code from that AppDelegate to here.
然后将该代码从AppDelegate复制到这里。
Okay, the code is identical from every app.
好的，每个应用程序的代码都是相同的。
The only difference between any of those things is this
它们之间唯一的区别就是这个
one string right here.
一个字符串。
You see that string?
你看到那个字符串?
That's the name of that xcmodeld file, so
这就是xcmodeld文件的名称
datamodeld file.
datamodeld文件。
So with our core data example,
以我们的核心数据为例，
this string would be CoreDataExample.
这个字符串就是CoreDataExample。
When we went back and created it on our own with new file,
当我们用新文件创建它时，
of course, we called it Model.
当然，我们称之为模型。
So just make sure this string matches the name of the file,
所以要确保这个字符串匹配文件的名称，
the xcmodel datamodeld file, okay?
xcmodel datamodeld文件?
So that's what you need to do if you didn't do the use
如果你不使用它，那就是你需要做的
Code Data originally you are going back and
代码数据最初你要回去
adding it- just copy and paste.
添加-只是复制和粘贴。
It's only this one var really, it does provide another thing
它只是一个var，它提供了另一个东西
in your AppDelegate which is a function called saveContext.
在AppDelegate中，这是一个叫做saveContext的函数。
It's a very simple little function.
这是一个非常简单的函数。
I'm gonna show you how you could write it yourself.
我来告诉你怎么自己写。
If you wanna copy it in, you can.
如果你想复制它，你可以。
Also I notice that they have applicationWillTerminate which
另外，我注意到他们已经应用了
is this application, AppDelegate method,
是这个应用程序，AppDelegate方法，
that gets called right before you get terminated or
这在你被终止之前就被调用了
you terminate it in any way and they call saveContext.
你以任何方式终止它，它们调用saveContext。
Well, it's a kind of an idea, a good idea.
好吧，这是一种想法，一个好主意。
saveContext() just saves your database.
saveContext()只是保存数据库。
That's what saveContext does, all right?
这就是saveContext的作用?
So this is how you can make up if you didn't do it.
所以如果你不这样做，你就可以弥补。
So anyway, you can see that the only thing in here
无论如何，你可以看到这里唯一的东西
is this lazy var persistentContainer, and
这是一个懒惰的var持久容器吗
I'm gonna talk all about persistentContainer,
我要讲的是persistentContainer，
because that's the thing that essentially contains
因为这是本质上包含的东西
your database, all right?
您的数据库?
But let's go back and talk about the visual map.
让我们回过头来讨论一下视觉地图。
Cuz we have to have a visual map before we can do anything
因为我们必须要有一个可视的地图才能做任何事情
in our database because we have to have some things in
在我们的数据库中，因为我们需要一些东西
our database, some objects and things like that.
我们的数据库，一些对象之类的东西。
And Core database stores things in this kind of very
Core database在这方面存储东西
straightforward way.
直接的方法。
It looks very object-oriented in our code because
它在我们的代码中看起来很面向对象
in Core Data terms it's storing entities,
在Core Data术语中，它是存储实体，
which look like classes to our code.
这看起来像是我们代码的类。
Attributes, which look like vars on our classes.
属性，在我们的类中看起来像vars。
And relationship, which just look like vars that point to
关系，看起来像vars
other objects in the database, other entities, etc.
数据库中的其他对象、其他实体等。
And so we're gonna use this what I'm calling a storyboard.
所以我们要用这个我称之为故事板。
It's not, don't get confused,
不是，别搞混了，
this is not a storyboard, okay?
这不是故事板，明白吗?
You know what a storyboard is, your Interface Builder thing.
你知道故事板是什么，你的接口生成器。
But it's kind of like a storyboard,
但它有点像故事板，
that's why it's in quotes for databases.
这就是为什么它在引用数据库的原因。
It's a graphical, visual editor to create and
这是一个图形化的可视化编辑器
describe all these entities, attributes and relationships,
描述所有这些实体、属性和关系，
okay, that's what we're gonna do here.
这就是我们要做的。
So let's start by adding an entity.
让我们从添加一个实体开始。
Very easy, we go down to this button on the bottom here
很简单，我们到下面这个按钮
called Add Entity.
添加实体。
Okay, to add an entity.
添加一个实体。
By the way, there's couple other things in that if you
顺便说一下，如果你的话，还有一些其他的东西
hold down on that button you'll see Add Fetch Request,
按住这个按钮，你会看到Add fetchrequest，
and Add Configuration.
并添加配置。
I don't have time to talk about those unfortunately,
我没有时间来讨论这些，
but especially Add Fetch Request is kind of a cool one.
尤其是添加fetchrequest是一种很酷的请求。
So, if you can take what I teach you here and extend it
所以，如果你能接受我教给你的东西并扩展它
by going and learning about that, that would be great.
通过学习和学习，那将是伟大的。
So you click Add Entity,
点击添加实体，
it creates a new entity called Entity.
它创建了一个名为entity的新实体。
Cuz it doesn't know what name you want for it yet.
因为它还不知道你想要什么名字。
And like I say, this analogous to a class.
就像我说的，类似于一个类。
Now in our code we're gonna see any instances of this
在我们的代码中，我们将看到任何实例
entity as instances of a class called NSManagedObject.
实体作为一个类的实例，称为NSManagedObject。
So NSManagedObject super important in Core Data.
NSManagedObject在Core Data中非常重要。
It is the super class or the class of everything that
它是所有东西的超类或类
comes, all these entities that come out of the database.
来，所有这些从数据库中出来的实体。
It's like the thing that represents them in our code,
就像在我们的代码中代表它们的东西一样，
and we'll see all about that.
我们将会看到这些。
So for my kind of slides here,
我这里的幻灯片，
what I'm gonna do is create a database that would have
我要做的是创建一个数据库
stuff like we got from Twitter.
像我们从Twitter得到的东西。
So it's gonna have tweets and
它会有推文和
we're gonna have Twitter users.
我们会有推特用户。
So those are gonna be two entities that we have and
这就是我们所拥有的两个实体
you're gonna see eventually, we're gonna have Tweet and
你会看到最终，我们会有推特和
TwitterUser classes in our code and
我们代码中的TwitterUser类
we're gonna access vars and all that stuff.
我们将访问vars和所有这些东西。
So I'm gonna rename this entity,
我要重命名这个实体，
this, that I added that was defaulted to entity,
我补充说，这是对实体的违约，
I'm gonna rename it and call it Tweet.
我把它重命名为Tweet。
So this is gonna be the first entity that I'm creating
这将是我创建的第一个实体
in the database.
在数据库中。
Now, an entity can have attributes.
现在，一个实体可以具有属性。
Those are kind of like vars, and relationships.
这有点像vars和关系。
Those are like vars that point to other entities.
这些就像vars指向其他实体。
And I told you this fetched properties down at the bottom,
我告诉过你们，这是在底部取的，
I'm not gonna talk about.
我不会讲的。
Very cool, but not gonna talk about them.
很酷，但不会谈论它们。
Not just time-wise.
不仅仅是时间。
So let's go and add some attributes to this entity.
让我们添加一些属性到这个实体。
Real easy, you click this plus button,
很简单，点击这个+按钮，
there's also an Add Attribute button,
还有一个Add属性按钮，
see it down in the lower right hand corner there.
在右下角看到它。
But I'm gonna click this little plus
但我要点击这个加号
button right there under the section called Attributes.
按钮就在属性栏下面。
And when I do there it adds a new attribute called attribute
当我在那里做的时候，它会添加一个叫做属性的新属性
and I'm gonna edit its name directly,
我要直接编辑它的名字，
just like I did the entity name.
就像我做实体名称一样。
I'm gonna change this to be text.
我要把它改成文本。
So, this is gonna be our tweet text, the 140 characters
这是我们的tweet文本，140个字符
of the tweet is gonna be this particular attribute.
这条推特将会是这个特殊的属性。
Now, notice as soon as I did that, I got an error.
注意，一旦我这么做了，就会出错。
In the corner there, this red error.
在角落里，这个红色的错误。
And the reason for
的原因
that is all attributes have to have a type.
这是所有属性都必须有类型。
They can't just be undefined type like this one is.
它们不能只是像这样的未定义类型。
You see where it says the type is undefined.
你可以看到它说的类型是未定义的。
So, we need to change that to be a type.
所以，我们需要把它变成一种类型。
And it's really easy, right there where it says undefined.
这很简单，在这里没有定义。
We're just going to mouse down,
我们要把鼠标往下拉，
it's gonna bring up a menu and we can choose our type.
它会打开一个菜单，我们可以选择我们的类型。
Now, these are the types we have to choose from.
现在，这些是我们必须选择的类型。
A lot of different numeric types like 16-bit integers,
很多不同的数字类型，比如16位整数，
32-bit integer, etc.
Doubles, floats, can a be string of course,
双打，花车，当然可以是字符串，
a Boolean value, a date which is going to look like a date,
一个布尔值，一个看起来像一个日期的日期，
you know, the date struct in our code.
你知道，我们代码中的日期结构。
And binary data which is gonna look like the data struct
而二进制数据看起来像数据结构
inside our code.
在我们的代码。
So, these are gonna map to very familiar data types
这些会映射到非常熟悉的数据类型
that we see.
我们看到的。
There is that one at the bottom there,
在底部有一个，
transformable, another thing I'm not gonna talk about.
转换，另一件事我不打算讲。
But transformable allows you to store anything
但是，transformable可以存储任何东西
into the database by converting it to a data, and
将其转换为数据，然后进入数据库
then converting it back on the way out.
然后把它转换回来。
And so if you pick transformable there,
如果你选择transformable，
you're gonna have to do some extra work.
你得做点额外的工作。
To tell Core Data about that transformation, and that's why
告诉Core Data关于这个转换的信息，这就是为什么
I don't really have time to tell you about, but just know
我没有时间告诉你，只是知道而已
that if you wanted to store something like a CGRect.
如果你想存储类似CGRect的东西。
Actually, if I was going to store a CGRect, I might use
实际上，如果我要存储一个CGRect，我可能会用到
the function, there's some function called something like
函数有一些函数
NSStringFromCGRect.
NSStringFromCGRect。
It gives you a string, and
它给你一个字符串
then there's NSCGRectFromString or
还有NSCGRectFromString或
something like that.
就像这样。
So I'd probably store it as a string,
我可能把它存储为字符串，
but if I had something more complicated than that,
但如果我有更复杂的东西，
then I might use a transformable.
然后我可以用一个可转换的。
All right, these attributes here are going to be accessed,
这些属性将被访问，
we're gonna get and set their values.
我们将得到并设置它们的值。
Well actually, we're not going to do this but fundamentally
实际上，我们不会这样做，但从根本上说
the way you do it is you have these two methods,
你的方法是，你有这两种方法，
value(forKey) and setValue (forKey).
值(forKey)和setValue(forKey)。
And I'll talk about how we're gonna use that, but
我会讲到如何使用它，但是
that's how we're gonna set and get the values on an entity.
这就是我们如何设置和获取一个实体的值。
Notice the error went away as soon as we
注意，错误一开始就消失了
gave this thing, a type.
给这个东西，一种类型。
So here I'm gonna add some more attributes, identifier,
这里我要添加一些属性，标识符，
which is just some string that identifies the tweet and
哪个是用来识别tweet的字符串
then created, which was when it was tweeted.
然后创建了，这是在推特上。
Notice I'm setting created's type here to be date because
注意，这里设置的是日期，因为
it is a date, obviously, when the thing was created.
很明显，这是一个日期。
Now this is one way to look at our entities and attributes,
这是观察我们的实体和属性的一种方法，
this kind of table form.
这种表格。
But we can actually look at it in graphical form as well.
但我们也可以用图形形式来观察它。
If you see down in the corner where it says editor style.
如果你看到角落里有编辑风格。
If I click on the other button there,
如果我点击这里的另一个按钮，
the one that looks a little more like a graph,
这个看起来更像图形，
then it shows me the same thing but
然后它向我展示了同样的东西
in this graphical form.
在这个图形的形式。
It's even on graph paper, all right?
它甚至在坐标纸上，对吧?
And in this form right here we can do
在这个表格中我们可以做
all the things that we did in the other one.
我们在另一个中做的所有事情。
For example, I can still add entity here.
例如，我还可以在这里添加实体。
So I'm gonna add another entity for my Twitter User,
所以我要为我的推特用户添加另一个实体，
this is people who tweet.
这是推特的人。
And there it is, it called it entity again,
它又称它为实体，
that's the default.
这是默认的。
We'll set its name to be TwitterUser.
我们将把它的名字设为TwitterUser。
All right, so we now have two entities, you see on there.
好的，现在我们有两个实体，在这里。
What's kinda cool is as you drag these entities around,
很酷的是当你拖动这些实体时，
this, this kind of editor, this graphical
这个，这个编辑器，这个图形
editor, will automatically kind of keep them spaced apart
编辑器，会自动将它们隔开
from each other.
从对方。
Which is kind of fun, especially since they're going
这很有趣，特别是因为他们要去
to start having wires connecting them because
开始连接它们，因为
they're going to start having relationships
他们会开始谈恋爱
to each other as you're going to see in a moment.
你们马上就能看到彼此。
We can add attributes in this graphical style as well- you
我们也可以在这个图形风格中添加属性——你
can edit those right in there just by double clicking on
可以通过双击来编辑这些吗
them, change whatever you want.
他们，改变你想要的。
So, here I got a screenName, now of course I got an error
这里我有一个截图，当然我有一个错误
again because I didn't set the type of that screenName.
因为我没有设置那个屏幕名的类型。
So, in this view you set the types by bringing up
在这个视图中，你设置了类型
the inspector.
检查员。
So you just bring up your normal inspector,
你只要把你的检查官带上来，
attribute inspector.
属性检查器。
And the, here you can see it's inspecting screenName,
这里你可以看到它在检查屏幕名称，
it's got the name there.
名字就在这里。
There's some other things in here like transient,
这里还有一些其他的东西，比如短暂的，
indexed, optional.
索引,可选的。
By the way, that optional doesn't mean this is optional
顺便说一下，这个可选并不意味着这是可选的
like the Swift thing optional.
就像快速的东西是可选的。
This is optional like in SQL database terms, right.
这在SQL数据库术语中是可选的。
In relational database optional.
在关系数据库中可选的。
So I'm not gonna talk about any of the database
我不会讲任何数据库
You rarely need to set any of these properties right here.
你很少需要在这里设置这些属性。
stuff of it.
的东西。
But you do need to set the type.
但是您需要设置类型。
So we're not gonna talk about that, but
所以我们不会讨论这个，但是
we have to set the type right here.
我们必须在这里设置类型。
And the screenName, of course, is a string.
当然，屏幕名是一个字符串。
So I'm just gonna change it to a string.
我把它改成一个字符串。
I'm adding another attribute to the TwitterUser,
我给TwitterUser添加了另一个属性，
this one is the name, the person's actual name,
这个是名字，这个人的真名，
not their @ sign handle, but their actual name.
不是他们的@符号句柄，而是他们的实际名字。
Now we've built a couple of entities with a bunch of
现在我们已经建立了一些实体
attributes on them, okay, and this is gonna look like
它们的属性，好的，这个看起来是这样的
classes with vars in our code eventually.
最终在我们的代码中使用vars的类。
But what about relationships, obviously a Tweet and
但关系呢，显然是一条推文
a TwitterUser have a relationship to each other.
TwitterUser之间有一个关系。
And to create relationships between things we just
并建立我们之间的关系
Ctrl+drag, this is our favorite gesture in Xcode and
Ctrl +拖动，这是我们在Xcode中最喜欢的手势
we're using it again.
我们再次使用它。
Ctrl+drag to create a relationship
Ctrl +拖动来创建关系
between two things.
两件事之间的关系。
And it actually doesn't matter which direction you Ctrl+drag,
不管你按哪个方向拖动，
because you're creating kind of a bidirectional
因为你在创造一种双向性
relationship.
的关系。
So here, I did Ctrl+drag, and it automatically created this
在这里，我按Ctrl +拖动，它自动创建了这个
relationship, which it called newRelationship on both sides.
关系，这是双方的新关系。
And this relationship is essentially just gonna be
这种关系本质上就是
a var in our class.
我们班的一个var。
But the var's type is either going to be the type, if it's
但var的类型要么是类型，如果是
like a Tweet, you know, it's gonna be a single one, or
就像一条推特，你知道，它会是一个单一的，或者
it could be an NSSet, if it's many of them.
它可以是NSSet，如果是很多的话。
Like a Twitter user might have many tweets, and
就像推特用户可能有很多推文
I'll talk about that in a moment.
我一会儿会讲到这个。
So, from a Tweet's perspective this relationship to
所以，从推特的角度来看这段关系
a TwitterUser is the Tweeter.
推特用户就是Tweeter。
The person who tweeted this tweet.
推特这条推文的人。
So, I'm going to change the name of this relationship on
所以，我要改变这段关系的名称
the Tweet side to be tweeter instead of newRelationship,
推特侧面是tweeter而不是newRelationship，
which was the default.
这是默认的。
But, on the other, okay, so that's why I call it tweeter.
但另一方面，这就是为什么我把它叫做tweeter。
On the other side the TwitterUser from its
另一边是TwitterUser
perspective though, okay, the relationship of the tweet is
不过，这条推特的关系是
the tweets that this Twitter user has tweeted.
推特用户在推特上发布的推文。
Okay, it's not tweeter, the Twitter user is the tweeter,
这不是tweeter,Twitter用户是tweeter，
so he would never call this relationship tweeter.
所以他绝不会把这种关系称为推特。
He's gonna call this relationship tweets
他会把这种关系称为推特
because this is the tweet.
因为这是推特。
Now notice that's plural, okay,
注意这是复数形式，
we'll talk about that in a second.
我们马上就会讲到。
Notice that when we do this, Xcode tracks if I'm inspecting
注意，当我们这样做的时候，Xcode会跟踪
the tweet's relationship there on the TwitterUser side,
在推特用户一边，这条推特的关系，
it knows the inverse.
它知道逆。
It knows that tweeter goes the opposite direction,
它知道推特是反方向的，
there's always gonna be an inverse relationship.
总会有一个逆关系。
So let's talk about that tweets being a plural right?
让我们来讨论一下，tweets是一个复数，对吧?
So a tweet can only have one tweeter.
所以一条推特只能有一个推特。
Only one person can have tweeted it, but
只有一个人可以在推特上发推特
a Twitter user can tweet thousands of tweets, okay?
一个推特用户可以发布数千条推文，对吧?
And so that's a little different
这有点不同
kind of relationship.
类型的关系。
So how do we specify that?
那么如何指定呢?
We call the tweets relationship the,
我们称推特关系为，
a to many relationship because obviously the Twitter
关系到很多关系，因为很明显Twitter
user can have many tweets.
用户可以有很多tweet。
So that's called to many in database parlance, and
这就叫很多数据库术语
you set that right in the Inspector.
你把它设置在检查器里。
So you just click on that tweets and
你只需点击这个推文就可以了
you go over here to where it says Type,
你到它说类型的地方，
and instead of having it be To One you're gonna change it
而不是让它变成一个你要改变它
to be To Many, okay, so now it's a to many relationship.
对很多人来说，这是一种关系。
Right there, you can see that it's changed a little bit as,
在这里，你可以看到它的变化有点像，
and we'll show that in a second.
我们马上就会展示出来。
But the type of this relationship now on the tweet
但这段关系现在在推特上
side is still type NSManagedObject,
side仍然是NSManagedObject类型，
because it points to another entity in the database.
因为它指向数据库中的另一个实体。
And we know that the objects in the database
我们知道数据库中的对象
are represented by an NSManagedObject.
由NSManagedObject表示。
So that's gonna be the type of that var.
这就是var的类型。
Although we're eventually gonna make it even better than
尽管我们最终会做得更好
that, but on the other side though,
但另一方面，
the type of that var is NSSet of NSManagedObject, okay?
var的类型是NSManagedObject的NSSet ?
Now NSSet, there is a Swift struct called set.
现在NSSet，有一个叫做set的Swift结构。
It's a generic type, it's just like an array where you have
它是一个泛型类型，它就像一个数组
to say what's in an array,
要说出数组中的内容，
same thing with a set you have to say what's in it.
同样的，你必须说出它里面有什么。
NSSet is kind of an older Objective-C kind of set.
NSSet是一种更老的objective - c类型的集合。
It's not generic, it's untyped.
它不是一般的，它是无类型的。
The things in NSSet are any, which we kinda need a little
NSSet中的东西都是，我们需要一点
bit here cuz we really don't know what kinds of things
因为我们真的不知道什么东西
are in there.
是在那里。
However, in your code you can cast from this NSSet
然而，在您的代码中，您可以从这个NSSet中进行转换
of NSManagedObject to a set of what you know to be in there
NSManagedObject的一组你知道的在那里
using as question mark, and
使用作为问号，和
if that in fact is what's in there, it will work.
如果这实际上是在那里，它就会起作用。
So that's the NSSet there.
这是NSSet。
One last thing I'm gonna show you here before
最后我要向你们展示的是
we get back to the slides is this Delete Rule.
我们回到幻灯片是这个删除规则。
You see the delete rule on the,
你看到了删除规则，
clicked on tweets on here so we're inspecting tweets.
点击这里的推文，我们就会检查推文。
And this delete rule tells you what happens
这个删除规则告诉你发生了什么
to the pointed-to tweets if we deleted this Twitter user.
如果我们删除了这个Twitter用户，就会有一个指向。
Cuz if I delete this Twitter user,
如果我删除这个推特用户，
does that mean I delete all of the Twitter user's tweets?
这是否意味着我删除了所有的推特用户的推文?
Well, it depends on this delete rule right here.
这取决于这里的删除规则。
this delete rule is saying nullify, which would mean no.
这个删除规则说的是nullify，这意味着没有。
So right now,
现在,
Those tweets would stay in the database, and their tweeter
这些推文将留在数据库中，以及他们的推特
will be set to nil because their tweeter got deleted.
将被设置为nil，因为他们的tweeter被删除了。
But there is a cascading delete rule, which would say
但是有一个级联删除规则，也就是说
if I delete this thing then delete everything that it
如果我删除了这个东西，然后删除它
points to, just go right down the graph and
指向，直接沿着图走
delete everything.
删除一切。
So that's what controls what happens when you delete.
这就是控制当你删除时发生的事情。
Now I'm not gonna ask you to even do delete;
现在我不会要求你删除;
I guess I might ask you an extra credit to do delete in
我想我可能会要你额外的学分来做删除
assignment five.
作业5。
Because deletion kinda- you're really gonna know what
因为删除，你真的会知道
you're doing- when you can delete things, and
你在做——当你可以删除东西的时候
what kind of delete rules you want.
你想要什么样的删除规则。
But I just want to let you know that you specify
但我只是想让你知道你的指定
the delete rule right here in the inspector.
删除规则在检查器中。
Okay, now that you've defined all your entities, attributes
好的，现在你已经定义了所有的实体，属性
in relationships, then what can we do with these things?
在人际关系中，我们能做些什么呢?
Well to do anything with it we need to get a hold of them
为了做任何事情，我们需要掌握它们
in our code, grab onto them basically, and
在我们的代码中，基本上抓住它们
to do that we need another important class,
我们需要另一个重要的课程，
NSManagedObjectContext, so I told you
NSManagedObjectContext，我告诉过你
all those things in the database are NSManagedObjects,
数据库中的所有东西都是nsmanagedobject，
you need an NSManagedObjectContext,
你需要一个NSManagedObjectContext,
which represents a database to do anything with them,
它表示数据库对它们做任何事情，
to get any of them, to create any of them, etc,
为了得到它们中的任何一个，
this is the hub around which Core Data activity turns,
这是核心数据活动转的中心，
as I say there.
就像我说的。
So how do I get one of these NSManagedObjectContext?
那么如何得到NSManagedObjectContext呢?
And the answer is, you need a persistentContainer.
答案是，你需要一个persistentContainer。
Woo-hoo, and you know where to get one of those.
哇哦，你知道哪里可以买到。
You just click, Use Core Data, and
你只需点击，使用核心数据，然后
it's gonna appear in your AppDelegate.
它会出现在你的AppDelegate中。
You're gonna get that lazy var,
你会得到那个懒惰的var，
that's called persistentContainer.
这就叫做persistentContainer。
And that is gonna be a persistentContainer.
这将是一个持续的容器。
And from that you can get the context.
这样你就能得到上下文。
Now, if you have the lazy var in your AppDelegate,
现在，如果你的AppDelegate中有一个懒惰的var，
How the heck do you call that var?
你怎么叫那个var ?
How do you get that var?
如何得到var ?
And this is how you do it, okay?
这就是你的做法，明白吗?
You get a copy of the shared UIApplication, now,
你会得到一个共享UIApplication的拷贝，
we didn't talk about this but your app has this one and
我们没有讨论这个，但是你的应用有这个
only UIApplication object that represents your application
只有表示应用程序的UIApplication对象
and you get it by doing UIApplication.shared,
你通过uiapplic. shared，共享，
it's a var.
这是一个var。
Static var in UIApplication class.
UIApplication类中的静态var。
Gives you the shared one.
给你一个共享的。
Then you're gonna access this var in UIApplication which is
然后在UIApplication中访问这个var
its delegate.
它的代表。
Now, its delegate is automatically set up for
现在，它的委托是自动设置的
you to be this Swift class AppDelegate that you see
你可以看到这个Swift类AppDelegate
always; we always put it off in Supporting Files and
总是;我们总是把它放在支持文件中
get it out of our way, but it's created for you,
把它从我们的道路上拿出来，但它是为你创造的，
it's a nice little class.
这是一个很好的小课堂。
We're going to talk about the application life cycle, and
我们将讨论应用程序生命周期
where it fits in, in a little bit, but for now all
它在哪里合适，在一点上，但现在呢
you need to know is you can get AppDelegate, and you want
你需要知道，你可以得到AppDelegate，你想要
to send persistentContainer to it to get that var, but of
将persistentContainer发送给它以获得var，但是
course you have to as it to be the AppDelegate class first.
当然，必须先将它作为AppDelegate类。
So this is the code you're going to use.
这就是你要用到的代码。
(UIApplication.shared.delegate as!
AppDelegate) All that in one expression
(AppDelegate)在一个表达式中
dot persistentContainer now you're gonna get this
点persistentContainer现在你会得到这个
persistentContainer, and notice I'm doing as
坚持容器，注意我做的是
exclamation point this will crash if my App Delegate is
感叹号如果我的应用程序委托，它会崩溃
not in fact App Delegate, but it's already wired up
实际上不是App委托，而是已经连接起来了
to be that for you when you create a new project,
当你创建一个新项目时，
so that should never be a problem.
所以这绝不是一个问题。
Okay? So
好吧?所以
now I have this persistentContainer,
现在我有了这个persistentContainer，
I need to get the context out of it.
我需要从它那里得到上下文。
And, so,
所以,
the container has an awesome var called viewContext.
容器有一个可怕的var，称为viewContext。
And the viewContext is an NSManagedObjectContext that's
viewContext是NSManagedObjectContext
only suitable for use on the main queue.
仅适用于主队列。
This is in red,
这是红色的,
you know whenever you see anything in red on my slides,
每当你看到我的幻灯片上有红色的东西，
this means pay attention, it will matter for
这意味着要注意，这很重要
your homework, and in life, but
你的家庭作业，还有生活
you can only use this viewContext in the main queue,
你只能在主队列中使用这个viewContext，
it called viewContext because you use it with your views,
它叫viewContext，因为你使用视图，
okay, your UI views, that's why we call it viewContext.
你的UI视图，这就是为什么我们称它为viewContext。
So why do I make a point about this main queue?
为什么我要强调这个主队列呢?
Well, the reason I do that is because NSManagedObjectContext
我之所以这么做是因为NSManagedObjectContext
is not thread-safe.
不是线程安全的。
But I'm gonna talk you, talk to you about how we can do
但我要告诉你，我们该怎么做
multithreaded database stuff towards the end of this talk.
在此演讲结束时，多线程数据库内容。
All right, so now you have this viewContext then you can
现在有了这个viewContext
use it to do things.
用它来做事情。
Now, it's so
现在,就是这样的
{UIApplication.shared.delegate as!
Appdelegate).persistentContai- ner,
Appdelegate)。persistentContai——尼珥
that's kind of a messy line of code.
这是一种杂乱的代码。
There's a lot of, there's as and all these things in there.
这里有很多，还有所有这些东西。
So at times we'll just create a static version of
有时我们会创建一个静态版本
persistentContainer in our AppDelegate.
在我们AppDelegate persistentContainer。
Okay, we'll just call it the same thing.
我们把它叫做同样的东西。
persistentContainer but it's static and
持久容器，但它是静态的
it's just gonna return that messy line of code.
它会返回那个混乱的代码行。
So now we can get that persistentContainer with
现在我们可以得到这个持久容器
AppDelegate.persistentContai- ner.
AppDelegate。persistentContai——尼珥。
See what I did there?
看到我做的了吗?
I just made it easier to get up by making that be a static,
我只是让它变得更容易一些，
a class var, and we can do the same thing with viewContext,
一个类var，我们可以用viewContext做同样的事情，
you might create a static called viewContext and for
您可以创建一个名为viewContext的静态文件
the rest of these slides you can assume I've done this.
剩下的这些幻灯片你可以假设我已经做过了。
Which is good because typing that long messy thing would
这很好，因为打字很麻烦
make all my slides spill over the edge.
让我的幻灯片溢出来。
So I'm gonna use this shorter version as well.
所以我也要用这个简短的版本。
And you're welcome to create the static
你可以创建静态的
version in your AppDelegate if you want
如果需要，可以在AppDelegate中进行版本
to make your code a little cleaner.
为了让你的代码更简洁。
Now this viewContext in the persistentContainer
现在这个viewContext在persistentContainer中
There's one of them that represents your entire
其中一个代表你的整个
are shared.
是共享的。
database.
数据库。
So it's perfectly fine to create a single static
所以创建一个静态的完全没问题
that does this.
做这个。
By the way, what if you wanted multiple databases?
顺便说一下，如果你想要多个数据库呢?
You could even have multiple databases with
甚至可以有多个数据库
different schema.
不同的模式。
Very easy, if you go look at the code for
很简单，如果你看一下代码
persistentContainer in AppDelegate,
persistentContainer AppDelegate,
you'll see it's only like four lines of code.
你会看到它只有四行代码。
And you could just copy it to create a different
你可以复制它来创建一个不同的
persistentContainer using a different xcmodeld file.
使用不同的xcmodeld文件的persistentContainer。
Instead of using model according to the example,
而不是根据这个例子使用模型，
create another one with a different one and
用不同的方法创建另一个
you can just go file, new file and create another data model.
你可以点击文件，新建文件，创建另一个数据模型。
You could even create two persistent containers with
您甚至可以创建两个持久性容器
the same model.
相同的模型。
So they would be separate databases, but
所以它们是单独的数据库，但是
have the same model, the same entities to that and
有相同的模型，相同的实体吗
the same relationship to that.
同样的关系。
It's perfectly allowed as well.
这也是完全允许的。
But for everything you're going to do in this class, and
但对于你在这门课上要做的所有事情
for really with most apps,
对于大多数应用来说，
you're going to have one big database.
你将会有一个大数据库。
And you're going to have this one persistent container that
你将会有一个持久的容器
is the container for it.
是它的容器。
All right.
好吧。
So now I have a context in my hand, this viewContext.
现在我有了一个context在我的手里，这个viewContext。
And what can I do?
我该怎么办呢?
Well, of course, I can insert objects into the database.
当然，我可以将对象插入数据库。
I can delete objects from the database.
我可以从数据库中删除对象。
And I can query for objects in the database.
我可以查询数据库中的对象。
So, let's talk about all those things.
那么，让我们来谈谈这些事情。
Let's start with insert because until we insert some
让我们从插入开始，因为在插入一些之前
data in the database we can't do any of those other things.
数据库中的数据我们不能做其他的事情。
And the way you insert an object in the database, or
以及在数据库中插入对象的方式
a way to do it, and actually for
一种方法，实际上是为了
the next few slide I'm going to kind of show you the,
接下来的几张幻灯片，我将向你们展示，
the essentials.
的必需品。
But, we're eventually going to move up to a high level and
但是，我们最终会达到一个高水平
access this stuff in a much nicer way.
以一种更好的方式访问这些东西。
But I'll tell you the basics of it first.
但我会先告诉你它的基本原理。
So the basic way to put something in the database is
所以在数据库中放置东西的基本方法是
with this really interesting method.
有了这个很有趣的方法。
NSEntityDescription.insertNew- Object(forEntityName: into:
NSEntityDescription。insertNew对象(forEntityName:到:
context).
上下文)。
Okay, that's a mouthful, used to be even more of a mouthful
好吧，这是一口，原来是一口
before they renamed it.
之前重命名它。
And you just specify the name of the entity, so
你只需指定实体的名称
Tweet or TwitterUser.
推特或TwitterUser。
And you give it a context that is gonna be the viewContext
你给它一个context它将是viewContext
you got from the AppDelegate.
你从AppDelegate得到。
And boom, it's gonna create one of these in the database.
它会在数据库中创建一个。
Now all of its attributes will be nil.
它的所有属性都是nil。
Okay, although you can inspect the attributes in
虽然你可以检查属性
the data model editor and specify default value.
数据模型编辑器并指定默认值。
And so it might start out with the default value.
它可能以默认值开始。
But if it doesn't, then they'll start out as nil.
但如果它没有，那么它们将以nil开始。
Okay, so that's great.
好了,这很好。
I can now create one.
我现在可以创建一个。
And now I need to set those vars to have some value.
现在我需要设置这些vars有一些值。
I need to set the text of the tweet and things like that and
我需要设置推文的文本和类似的东西
I told you I'm gonna do this with value for key and
我告诉过你我要用valueforkey和
set value for key.
为关键的设置值。
So for example I wanted to set the let's say the text,
例如，我想设置文本，
I could just say tweet.
我只能说推特。
A set value for key quote text, to be a string.
一个键值文本的集合值，作为字符串。
And you can do dot notation here, with value for key path.
你可以在这里做点标记，用valueforkeypath。
That's what I'm showing in green right there.
这就是我用绿色表示的。
You can have, if you had a tweet you can actually set
如果你有一条推特，你可以设置
the tweet's tweeter's name, using this dot notation to set
推特的推特的名字，用这个点符号来设置
value for key path tweeter dot name and it would go through
valueforkeypath tweeter dot name，它会通过
the tweeter relationship which is kinda fun.
tweeter的关系很有趣。
I'm kinda going fast through this because this is a really
我讲得有点快，因为这是真的
terrible API.
可怕的API。
First of all it's got any in there so
首先它里面有任何东西
there's not type checking going on here, okay?
这里没有类型检查，明白吗?
You could say, set value date for key quote text, all right?
你可以说，为关键引号文本设置值日期?
And that would be perfectly accepted by Swift.
这将会被斯威夫特完全接受。
Date is an Any and quote text is a String, but
日期是一个Any，引用文本是字符串，但是
of course that's gonna fail miserably at run time, okay,
当然，这在运行时会失败，
because the text is a Atring.
因为文本是一个Atring。
So we're not really gonna use this API but this is
所以我们不会使用这个API，但这是
the underlying basic way that Core Data is doing this.
核心数据的基本方式是这样的。
Yes the key is just the name of the attribute, and
是的，关键是属性的名称，以及
the value is all the things we've talked about before.
这个值就是我们之前讨论过的所有东西。
I do have the blue Use Scalar Type there which
我有蓝色的使用标量类型
is interesting.
很有趣。
If the thing you're putting in the database is a flow or
如果你在数据库中输入的东西是流或
an Int32 or one of these things.
一个Int32或其中一个。
It's actually gonna be stored in a database as an NSNumber,
它实际上会被存储在数据库中作为NSNumber，
which is a class,
这是一个类,
it's an object, kind of generic holder of numbers.
它是一个对象，是数字的一般持有者。
But if you flip on the switch in the inspector in your data
但如果你在数据中打开检查器的开关
modeller for that attribute saying use a scalar type,
该属性的modeller使用标量类型，
then it'll make the type be double or int or whatever,
然后它会使类型为double或int等等，
instead of NSNumber, so.
而不是NSNumber,所以。
I know, you had a question?
我知道，你有问题吗?
>> Yes, so the question is, does set value reject
something where the types don't match?
某些类型不匹配的东西?
And the answer is, it can't.
答案是，它不能。
It doesn't know the type, the types are any,
它不知道类型，类型是any，
as long as it matches any- and everything matches any.
只要它匹配任何东西，任何东西都匹配。
So, it can't.
所以,它不能。
There's no way for it to have enough information to reject.
没有足够的信息来拒绝。
As long as it matches any, it'll accept that as the type.
只要它匹配任何，它就会接受它作为类型。
And then at runtime, it will crash.
然后在运行时，它会崩溃。
If you try to set a date to be into a string field.
如果您尝试将日期设置为字符串字段。
>> So when it's like [INAUDIBLE]
save context,
拯救环境,
do you have to like make it go through.
你必须喜欢让它通过吗?
Or is it. >> Go and remove.
还是。> >去删除。
>> [CROSSTALK] >> What do you
mean go and remove it?
意思是去把它拿走?
Remove what?
删除什么?
Yeah, we'll talk about saving in this.
是的，我们会谈到储蓄。
So, the question is,
所以,问题是,
when the app terminates it does save context and
当应用程序终止时，它可以保存上下文
they're trying to save this, we'll talk all about saving in
他们想挽救这个，我们来谈谈储蓄
a minute cause that's an important piece of this.
一分钟的原因，这是很重要的一点。
That's the keys and values, pretty straightforward there;
这是键和值，很简单;
in fact we're going to talk about saving right now.
事实上，我们现在要讲的是储蓄。
We do a nice lead in.
我们做得很好。
All these changes that you make with that set value even
所有这些变化都是用这个集合的值来做的
insert entity description for
插入实体描述
entity name context whatever that thing is called.
实体名称上下文，不管叫什么东西。
All that stuff only happens in memory,
所有这些只发生在记忆中，
if you want that to actually happen permanently in
如果你想让它永久地发生
the database you need to save it.
您需要保存它的数据库。
And you do that by telling the context,
你这样做的前提是，
like that view context thing, to save with the method save.
像这样的视图上下文，用方法保存。
It couldn't be simpler, except that it can throw.
它不可能更简单，除了它可以扔。
Save is a method that can throw because
Save是一种可以抛出的方法
maybe there's a problem writing out to the database.
可能有一个问题写到数据库。
And there's many problems that could happen writing
还有很多问题可能会发生
out to the database.
到数据库。
And you need to look at documentation and
你需要看看文档和
kind of figure out what they all are.
弄清楚它们都是什么。
But the take home message here is you do need to save.
但这里要传达的信息是，你需要保存。
If you don't save, that substance is gonna be lost
如果你不存，那东西就会丢失
when your app exists or whatever.
当你的应用程序存在时。
So you definitely just save.
所以你一定要保存。
And especially when talking about multithreaded Core Data.
特别是在讨论多线程核心数据时。
And one thread is working.
一个线程在工作。
That thread needs to save if it wants any of the other
如果线程想要另一个线程，则需要保存它
threads to see the work that it's done.
线程来查看它完成的工作。
Okay, so you can use try question mark here, remember,
你可以在这里用问号，记住，
which means try and
这意味着试着
if it fails, just return nil and ignore it.
如果失败，则返回nil并忽略它。
You can do that, if you don't mind that it didn't save.
如果你不介意的话，你可以这么做。
And the kinda things that can happen, saving errors.
还有一些可能发生的事情，比如保存错误。
You could obviously have file system problems,
你可能会遇到文件系统问题，
your disk is full or something like that.
你的磁盘已经满了，或者类似的东西。
But you can also have inconsistencies in
但你也可以有不一致的地方
the database, maybe you had conflicting
数据库，也许你有冲突
data of two threads trying to save to the same database, and
两个线程试图保存到同一个数据库的数据
they've tried to write over the top of each other,
他们试着互相写，
those kind of things.
这样的事情。
Again, a lot of those problems you're not gonna have,
这些问题很多都没有，
unless you build a pretty complicated,
除非你建立一个相当复杂的，
multithreaded application, or something like that,
多线程应用程序，或者类似的东西，
but, again, you gotta check the documentation, I couldn't,
但是，你必须检查文档，
it would take too long for me to go through all of it.
我要花很长时间才能完成所有的工作。
Okay now, as I said value forKey and setValue forKey.
现在，正如我所说的值forKey和setValue forKey。
Really ugly,
真的很丑,
What we really want to do is be able to set these vars
我们真正想做的是能够设置这些vars
as vars, we just wanna have a var called text
作为vars，我们只需要一个名为text的var
somewhere that we can set.
我们可以在某个地方设置。
And of course we're exactly going to do that.
当然，我们会这样做。
And the way we're going to do that is create a subclass of
我们要做的就是创建一个子类
NSManagedObject, instead of having NSManagedObject in
NSManagedObject，而不是NSManagedObject
the database we doing set-value, get-value on it.
我们做的数据库设置值，在它上面的值。
Instead we're going to create a subclass of NSManageObjects
相反，我们将创建NSManageObjects的子类
and it's going to have vars on there for all the attributes,
它的所有属性都是vars，
like text, and screen name and all those things.
比如文本，屏幕名称等等。
And Xcode will generate all that code for
Xcode会生成所有的代码
you behind the scenes,
你在幕后,
you don't have to do any work to make that happen.
你不需要做任何工作来实现这一点。
Quite quite simple, so let's look and see how we do that.
很简单，让我们看看怎么做。
You do that by inspecting the entity.
你通过检查实体来做到这一点。
So here I've chosen tweet.
这里我选择了tweet。
Okay, not any of its attributes but
好的，不是它的任何属性，而是
tweet itself, and I want to make it so
推特本身，我想这样做
it generates this magic code, and how do I do that?
它产生了这个神奇的代码，我该怎么做呢?
Well, if you go down on the inspector
好吧，如果你去找探长
a little ways you see it says Codegen.
你看到的一些方法，它说的是Codegen。
See that Codegen, that's for
看那个Codegen，它是for
generating this code, this magic code.
生成这个代码，这个神奇的代码。
Now, you actually have a couple of choices here for
现在，你有几个选择
the Codegen.
Codegen。
The default I believe is this one Class Definition.
默认情况下，我认为这是一个类定义。
If you choose this one it will generate that subclass for
如果你选择这个，它会生成那个子类
you and it will just work.
你和它只会工作。
Okay, you'll be able to access your tweets as a class
你可以把你的推文作为一个类来访问
called tweet.
称为tweet。
With all the vars.
var。
Now this sounds good and
这听起来不错
it is good; by the way if you do this class definition
它是好的;如果你做这个类定义
codegen it will not show up in your navigator.
它不会出现在你的导航器里。
It's all behind the scenes- you never really see this file
这都是幕后的事情——你从来没有真正看到过这个文件
that is, this codegen file that generates.
这就是生成的codegen文件。
So don't look for
所以不要找
it there if you put this on class definition.
如果你把这个放在类定义上。
This might even be the default actually.
这实际上可能是默认的。
To be Class Definition might be on.
可以定义为类定义。
But there's other choices in here.
但这里还有其他选择。
And the one we choose the most often is Category/Extension.
我们最常选择的是Category / Extension。
By the way, category just is the Objective-C word for
顺便说一下，category仅仅是objective - c的意思
extension.
扩展。
Objective-C has something like extensions called categories.
objective - c有类似于扩展的类别。
So that's why it says Category/Extension.
这就是Category /扩展名的原因。
But you can think in your mind that this just says extension.
但你可以在你的脑海中思考这只是说延伸。
And what this is gonna do is only generate an extension
它只会生成一个扩展
of your Tweet class.
你的推文类。
You have to actually write the Tweet class itself.
你必须自己写推文类。
But it's all gonna have only your code in it, or
但它只会有你的代码，或者
it could be empty if you want.
如果你愿意，它可能是空的。
The extension's gonna take care of all making the vars.
扩展会负责所有制作vars的工作。
Okay, the var magic right there.
这里的var魔法。
So let's see how this works.
我们来看看它是如何工作的。
Even when I switch to Category/Extension.
甚至当我切换到Category /扩展时。
Again, I don't get that extension showing up in
再一次，我没有得到这个扩展
my navigator.
我的导航器。
It's kind of hidden from you.
这是隐藏的。
Here I'm gonna add the extension way of doing it for
这里我要添加一个扩展的方法
TwitterUser too.
TwitterUser。
So both of them, both Tweet and TwitterUser, I'm gonna
所以他们都是推特和推特用户，我要
have an extension generated and, why do we like this one?
有一个扩展生成，为什么我们喜欢这个?
Because, a lot of times for
因为，很多时候
our Tweet or TwitterUser we want to add our own code.
我们的Tweet或TwitterUser我们想添加我们自己的代码。
Like in a tweet.
就像在一条微博。
Imagine you wanted to add a static method that took data
假设您想添加一个静态方法，以获取数据
from Twitter and turned it into a tweet in the database.
从推特(Twitter)到数据库的一条推文。
Where would you put that code?
你会把代码放在哪里?
Well, a great place to put it would be in a tweet class,
好吧，一个很好的地方是在推特上，
if there was such a thing.
如果有这样的事。
And so, you're in fact, going to create such a thing.
所以，事实上，你会创造出这样的东西。
And the extension is going to handle all of the var business
扩展将处理所有的var业务
for you.
给你。
If you did choose Manual/None, right here for Codegen,
如果你选择了Manual / None，就在这里for Codegen，
meaning don't do any Codegen, then you're doing value for
意思是不要做任何代码，然后你就可以做了
set value for key.
为关键的设置值。
Good luck with that, the code's gonna be a mess, okay?
祝你好运，代码会一团糟，明白吗?
So, we almost always do it this way with this extension.
我们通常用这种方法来做这个扩展。
Also, if we build our app using multiple modules
另外，如果我们使用多个模块构建我们的应用程序
like we have in Smash Tag, we have a framework module and
就像在Smash标签中一样，我们有一个框架模块
then we have the main module.
然后我们有主模块。
Then you're probably gonna wanna choose
然后你可能会选择
from this pull-down here where it says module,
从这个下拉，到模块，
current product module.
当前的产品模块。
I think if you have a single app that's not modularized
我想如果你有一个没有模块化的应用
like that you probably don't need to set that, but
你可能不需要设置它，但是
in a multi-modual app you probably do want to.
在一个你可能想要的多功能应用程序中。
So, since we've chosen here to create only the extension,
既然我们选择在这里创建扩展，
we obviously need to write the code for the classes Tweet And
显然，我们需要为类Tweet编写代码
TwitterUser, we have to create those classes ourselves.
TwitterUser，我们必须自己创建这些类。
So how do we do that?
怎么做呢?
Well, just like we create anything,
就像我们创造任何东西一样，
we use file, new file.
我们使用文件，新文件。
Then we do file, new file, this time we are back
然后我们做文件，新文件，这次我们回来了
to saying it's a cocoa touch class because NSManageObject.
说它是一个cocoa触摸类，因为NSManageObject。
Why is it code called cocoa touch class,
为什么它被称为cocoa touch类，
we wanna make sure we set our super class to be in its
我们要确保我们的超类在它的
managed object, right?
管理对象,对吧?
So, I'm creating a class called Tweet,
我正在创建一个名为Tweet的类，
you see, which is a subclass of NSManagedObject.
你看，这是NSManagedObject的子类。
And is gonna create this for us.
然后为我们创建这个。
See? Class Tweet: NSManagedObject.
看到了吗?类微博:NSManagedObject。
No code in there.
没有代码。
That space is for us, we get write anything we want.
这个空间是给我们的，我们可以写任何我们想要的东西。
The code that does the vars is in that extension which we
做vars的代码在这个扩展中
don't even see, but but
看不见，但是
I'm gonna show it to yo in a second here.
我要在这里展示给你看。
Notice that I picked the name of this class Tweet
注意，我选择了这个类Tweet的名称
to be the same as the name of the entity in the database,
与数据库中的实体名称相同，
which, you want to do.
你想做什么。
It is possible to not do that by inspecting the entity
通过检查实体，不可能做到这一点
in the data model, but, don't do it.
在数据模型中，但是，不要这样做。
Just have the entity with the same name.
只有具有相同名称的实体。
People reading your code are going to expect this class,
阅读你的代码的人会期待这门课，
this subclass of NSManageObject that
NSManageObject的子类
represents a tweet.
代表一个tweet。
Entity to be called tweet, so called it that.
实体被称为tweet，因此被称为tweet。
Now, we've got an error here, I'll just created this class,
这里有一个错误，我创建这个类，
how I'm gonna possibly have an error,
我可能会有一个错误，
I'm done anything how could I've done anything wrong?
我做错了什么事?
Well, the problem the problem here is,
问题是，
really, Xcode has done something wrong.
真的，Xcode做错了什么。
When Xcode created this, it didn't seem to realize that
当Xcode创建这个的时候，它似乎并没有意识到这一点
NSManageObject is not in UIKit.
NSManageObject不是在UIKit中。
You see how it put import UIKit at the top?
你看到它如何在顶部导入UIKit了吗?
Really, what we need there is import CoreData, okay.
实际上，我们需要导入CoreData。
All the code that you write,
你写的所有代码，
any time you're doing something in CoreData,
任何时候你在CoreData做什么，
you have to import CoreData.
您必须导入CoreData。
It's a different framework that the UIKit so
这是一个不同的框架，UIKit
you must import it everywhere that you're going to use it.
你必须把它导入到你将要使用的地方。
Just like we had to import Twitter everywhere we want to
就像我们必须在任何地方进口Twitter一样
use that Twitter framework that I gave you.
使用我给你的Twitter框架。
So, I don't know why Xcode, I think it's just an oversight
所以，我不知道为什么Xcode，我认为这只是一个疏忽
Okay?
好吧?
that Xcode when you choose NSManagedObject
当你选择NSManagedObject时，这个Xcode
as your super class you should know, that's in Core Data so
作为你的超类，你应该知道，这是核心数据
it should be import Core Data there.
应该在那里导入核心数据。
Don't know why it doesn't do that.
不知道为什么不这么做。
So here I've created one for the TwitterUser class.
这里我为TwitterUser类创建了一个。
Again you can put anything you want in there.
你可以在里面放任何你想要的东西。
This is your class.
这是你的类。
You can do anything you want.
你可以做任何你想做的事。
All the stuff about the vars is off in
所有关于vars的东西都在里面
an extension somewhere.
一个扩展。
In fact, let's go take a look at that extension,
事实上，我们来看看这个扩展，
Even though it's not going to show up in your next navigator
即使它不会出现在你的下一个导航器中
what it looks like.
它看起来像什么。
you're probably never going to look at it.
你可能永远也不会去看它。
I thought I'd show it to you so
我想我应该给你看看
you understand a little bit what's going on.
你能理解发生了什么。
So, this is the extension, this generated for
这就是它的延伸
TwitterUser.
TwitterUser。
You see that is an extension
这是一个延伸
of the TwitterUser class, right?
在TwitterUser类中，对吧?
Remember extensions and it's got the vars.
记住扩展，它有vars。
They're defined not just name and screenName but
它们不仅定义了名称和屏幕名称，还定义了它们
it's got that relationship var tweets as well.
它也有关系var的推文。
All right?
好吧?
And look at the type of tweets.
看看推特的类型。
As promised, it's an NSSet, it's an optional because it
正如所承诺的，它是一个NSSet，它是可选的，因为它
comes out of the database as not set.
从数据库中出来，而不是设置。
It's gonna get set.
它会得到设置。
So these are the vars.
这些是vars。
And I'll talk a little bit about
我会讲一点
how these vars are actually implemented in a minute but
这些vars是如何在一分钟内实现的
all the vars are there.
所有的vars都在那里。
There's also some functions,
也有一些功能,
now at the bottom you see those functions,
在底部你可以看到这些函数，
those are kind of fun, those are convenience functions for
这些都很有趣，这些都是方便函数
adding and removing tweets from the tweets set
在推特上添加和删除推文
because NSSet is immutable, okay?
因为NSSet是不可变的，对吧?
It's not var verses let like swift things,
这不是var，像swift的东西，
NS set is kind of old Objective-C way, and NSSet,
NSSet是一种老的objective - c方式，NSSet，
like NSAttributedString, is immutable, cannot be changed,
像NSAttributedString一样，是不可变的，不能改变，
so how can I add any tweets to my database here?
那么，我该如何在我的数据库中添加任何tweet呢?
Well you used these functions instead, add to tweets,
你使用这些函数，添加到tweet，
remove from tweets, add to tweets,
删除推文，添加推文，
remove from tweets, there's a pair for doing a single tweet,
从推特上删除，有一对做一条推文，
and there having adding a whole bunch of tweets, or
在那里添加了一大堆推文，或者
removing a whole bunch of tweets, okay?
删除一大堆tweet，明白吗?
So you're definitely going to want those functions for
所以你肯定想要这些函数
your assignment five.
作业5。
Cuz you're gonna have some relationships where you're
因为你会有一些关系
gonna want to add them using these functions.
用这些函数相加。
Now it adds those functions for
现在它添加了这些函数
any too many relationship, any time you have a too many var
任何关系，任何时候你有太多的var
like tweets, it's going to add these functions automatically
就像tweets一样，它将自动添加这些功能
It actually put it in its own little extension, this file
它实际上把它放到了自己的扩展中，这个文件
in the extensions.
在扩展。
has two extensions in it, both through TwitterUser.
它有两个扩展，都是通过TwitterUser。
Any questions about extensions there or any of that?
关于扩展有什么问题吗?
Okay, let's look at tweets extension real quick.
好的，让我们快速浏览一下推特。
Couple other things to look at here that I didn't look
还有一些我没看的东西
in the other one.
在另一个。
Notice this static func called fetchRequest?
注意到这个静态func叫做fetchRequest吗?
Put that in your mind.
把这个放在你的脑子里。
I'm gonna talk about that in a few slides.
我将在几张幻灯片中谈到这个。
fetchRequest is a really cool little static func that will
fetchRequest是一个非常酷的静态func
give you something you can use to fetch tweets.
给你一些你可以用来获取推文的东西。
And if you call fetchrRquest on twitter users,
如果你在推特上调用fetchrRquest，
you'll get something to fetch twitter users.
你会得到一些推特用户的东西。
And we'll talk about all about fetch in a moment here.
我们一会儿会谈到取回。
Notice the type of tweeter, see the tweeter var.
注意推特的类型，看看tweeter var。
Its type is TwitterUser.
它的类型是TwitterUser。
Because of course that's what the tweeter is,
因为这就是推特的作用，
we control drag between the tweet and the tweeter user so
我们在推特和推特用户之间控制拖拽
that tweeter var is of course a tweeter user,
tweeter var当然是推特用户，
not an NSSet, because it's a two one relationship, okay,
不是NSSet，因为这是两种关系，
there's only one TwitterUser, who is my tweeter.
只有一个推特用户，我的推特用户。
And what about this @NSManaged?
那么这个@ nsmanaged呢?
Okay, @NSManaged I'm just gonna say it's magic.
好的，@ nsmanagedobi我只是想说它是神奇的。
It's not really magic.
它不是真正的魔法。
It's essentially something that says to the runtime, hey.
它本质上是对运行时说的。
When someone accesses this var,
当有人访问这个var时，
Core Data's gonna figure it out for you.
Core Data会为你找出答案。
And what Core Data does, is when you try to say
Core Data做的是，当你试着说
Tweet.created equals some date, it gets trapped
推特。创建等于某个日期，它被捕获
at a low level in the runtime and Core Data swoops in and
在运行时处于低水平，核心数据突然出现
does set value for key for you, okay.
为你的键设置值。
Same thing if you get the created var, it swoops in and
同样的，如果你得到了创建的var，它会俯冲进来
does value for key and gets it that way.
对键值的值是这样的。
But it's all happening at a low level behind the scenes.
但这一切都发生在幕后。
So this extension does satisfy the extension limitation where
所以这个延伸确实满足了扩展限制
it can't have any storage.
它没有任何存储空间。
All of the storage for these vars isn't in the database.
这些vars的所有存储都不在数据库中。
And when you ask for it.
当你要求的时候。
Or when you set it, it's using its value for
或者当你设置它的时候，它是在使用它的值
key instead of value for key, to set it in the database.
键值代替键值，将其设置在数据库中。
Now again, it sets in memory.
再一次，它在内存中设置。
You have to save it for
你必须把它存起来
it to actually go out into the database.
它会进入数据库。
But that what's happening.
但这发生了什么。
All right, so
好吧,那么
now that we have these class so here's some
现在我们有了这些类
code that creates a tweets and sets it's attributes, okay so
创建一个tweet并设置它的属性的代码，好的
let's look at this piece by piece and see what it does.
让我们来看看它是怎么做的。
The first thing is to create a tweet, we don't have to do
第一件事是创建一条tweet，我们不需要做
NSEntityDescription, Entity, insert Entity for name into
nUNK tydescription，实体，插入实体的名称
contacts, or whatever that huge, long terrible thing was-
联系，或者其他什么巨大的，长期可怕的事情
we can just say, tweet, parenthesis context.
我们可以说，推特，圆括号。
You just say what context, which means what database you
你只需要说明上下文，这意味着什么数据库
want the tweet to put in and it creates a new tweet.
想要推入推文并创建一条新的tweet。
Okay, just use a normal initializer for
好的，使用一个普通的初始化器
new things so that's super cool.
新的东西，所以这很酷。
That's one of the coolest features right there.
这是最酷的功能之一。
Not having to use an NSEntityDescription thing, so
不需要使用n情感描述的东西，所以
no more NSEntityDescription, we'll not have to do that.
没有更多的n情感描述，我们就不用这么做了。
And then here,
然后在这里,
I'm setting the text to be 140 characters of pure joy.
我把文本设定为140个纯粹的快乐。
And I don't have to say set value 140 characters of pure
我不需要说集合值140个纯的字符
joy for key text and have all these literal strings like
关键文本的乐趣，以及所有这些文字字符串
text in there in this untyped thing.
文本就在这里。
I just say tweet.text equals that.
我只是说推特。文本=。
And the same thing here with created, again, so we don't
同样的东西也在这里，我们没有
even have to worry about the thing, if we tried to say
如果我们想说的话，就连担心这件事都要担心
tweet.created equals quote hello, this Swift would say,
推特。创造等于引用hello，这个Swift会说，
no, created is of type Date, so you can't do that, so
不，创建的是类型日期，所以你不能那样做
it finds all of our, it type checks everything,
它找到所有的，它类型检查所有东西，
finds all of our possible errors.
找出所有可能的错误。
What about relationships, okay, setting relationships?
那么人际关系呢?
So here I've created another object, a TwitterUser and
这里我创建了另一个对象，TwitterUser
again I just set TwitterUser with a context,
再一次，我给TwitterUser设置了一个context，
I'll talk about that argument in just a second but
我一会儿会讲到这个论点
I told what database I wanna create in TwitterUser and
我告诉了我想在TwitterUser创建的数据库
I set my tweet's tweeter equal to that TwitterUser.
我设置了推特的tweeter等于TwitterUser。
So, it's exactly what you're, would imagine right?
所以，这正是你所想象的，对吧?
Just set it equal to Joe.
把它设为Joe。
And what's interesting about this is that when you set one
有趣的是，当你设置一个
side of a relationship, the other side gets updated
一方的关系，另一方得到更新
automatically, 100% of the time.
自动的，100%的时间。
This is call maintaining
这是呼叫保持
the integrity of the database, okay?
数据库的完整性?
And Core Data always maintains database integrity.
核心数据始终保持数据库完整性。
So, when you change one side relationship.
所以，当你改变了一段关系。
It changes the other.
它改变了。
So, that means for example if I say tweet.tweeter
这意味着如果我说tweeter。tweeter
equals Joe, then if I went over to the Joe side and
和Joe一样，如果我走到Joe这边
said hey give me Joe's tweets and I'm even gonna turn it
说，嘿，给我乔的推文，我甚至会把它转过去
into a Swift kind of set from an NSSet to a set of
从NSSet变成一组快速的集合
tweet because we know that's what tweets are, right?
推特，因为我们知道推特是什么，对吧?
Tweets are a set of Tweets, so I'm gonna as it to do that.
推文是一组推文，所以我要这么做。
Then I can say, if Joe's tweet contains that tweet print yes
然后我可以说，如果乔的推文包含了推特打印是的
and of course it is going to print yes.
当然，它会打印yes。
Because when I said tweet.tweeter = joe,
因为当我说tweet的时候。推特=乔,
it automatically got added to joe's tweets.
它自动添加到joe的tweets中。
That make sense?
这说得通吗?
And same thing the other way.
同理。
If I added a tweet into joe's tweets,
如果我在乔的推文中添加一条推文，
that tweet tweeter would automatically set to be joe.
推特推特将自动成为乔。
Okay? Both sides will always
好吧?双方将永远
point to each other.
指向对方。
You never have to do anything to make that happen.
你不需要做任何事情来实现它。
tweet.tweeter=joe is exactly
推特。推特=乔就是
the same as saying joe dot addToTweets tweet.
就像说joe dot addToTweets。
Remember addToTweets is one of those convenience functions
记住addToTweets是其中一个方便函数
that it created for us over there.
它是为我们创造的。
Now, notice the argument I used for
现在，注意我所使用的参数
the context to create the Twitter user there.
创建Twitter用户的上下文。
I didn't say AppDelegate.viewContext.
我没有说AppDelegate.viewContext。
I didn't use that same context bar that I had.
我没有使用以前的上下文栏。
I said tweet.manageObjectContext.
我说tweet.manageObjectContext。
In other words, I got, I found out what database the tweet is
换句话说，我找到了推特的数据库
in, and I put the Twitter user in the same database.
我把推特用户放在同一个数据库中。
And this is a common way of programming in Core Data
这是核心数据中常见的编程方式
where when you wanna get a context and
当你想要得到背景的时候
you already have a object in the database you
您已经在数据库中有了一个对象
ask the object you already have what context to use.
问一下你已经有什么背景的对象。
And you can see that if I ever change my code to not put this
你可以看到，如果我改变我的代码，不把它放上去
into this context, to put it into another context, at least
在此背景下，至少把它放到另一个环境中
the Twitter user and the tweet would always be together
推特用户和推特总是在一起
in whatever that context is.
在任何情况下。
So you can see why I used the tweets can't
所以你可以看到为什么我使用推文不能
manage object context here to create that instead of using
在这里管理对象上下文，而不是使用
the context again.
上下文。
So, it, it would work to say context, of course,
所以，它会说上下文，当然，
but I'm just saying there's a paradigm of development where
但我只是说有一个发展的范式
we're gonna try and use the context of related object.
我们将尝试使用相关对象的上下文。
So they end up in the same database for sure.
所以他们最终在同一个数据库中。
Okay?
好吧?
All right, so
好吧,那么
we can also use dot notation, because these are just vars.
我们也可以用点符号，因为这些只是vars。
So when I say tweet.tweeter, I get a TwitterUser object.
所以当我说tweet的时候。tweeter，我得到一个TwitterUser对象。
So, of course, I can say dot name on it and
当然，我可以在它上面写点名
set it equal to Joe Schmo, whatever, right?
把它设为Joe Schmo，对吧?
tweet.tweeter.name = "Joe Schmo", all right?
tweeter . tweeter . name = " Joe Schmo " ?
No restriction there on those vars.
没有限制在那些vars上。
All right, remember I told you about the scalars?
好吧，记得我告诉过你关于标量的事吗?
This is that switch I was telling you about before.
这就是我之前告诉你们的那个开关。
If you don't do this, then when you say,
如果你不这样做，当你说，
if you had an int, let's say you had retweet
如果你有一个int，假设你有retweet
count which was an int here let's say on Int32.
数数在这里是int，我们在Int32上说。
If you don't switch this button,
如果你不切换这个按钮，
then that's going to be an NSNumber not an Int32.
那将会是一个NSNumber而不是Int32。
But when you click this switch on,
但是当你点击这个开关时，
now that var will be of type Int32.
现在var将会是Int32型。
So you almost always want this for numbers.
所以你几乎总是想要这个数字。
99.9% of the time, you want to have this switch on.
Luckily, it's on by default so
幸运的是，默认情况下是这样的
you don't even have to think about it much, but
你甚至不用想太多，但是
I just wanted to let you know about it.
我只是想让你知道。
All right, so now lets talk about deletion.
好，现在我们来讨论删除。
Okay, now, I want to delete something from the database.
现在，我想从数据库中删除一些东西。
And that's incredibly easy,
这是令人难以置信的简单,
almost too easy because your data's precious you don't want
几乎太容易了，因为你的数据很宝贵，你不想要
to be deleting it to easily, but you do that by asking
要删除它很容易，但你要这样做
the context to delete the NSManagedObject, so you can
删除NSManagedObject的上下文，可以
pass any NSManagedObject to this method delete and
将任何NSManagedObject传递给此方法删除和
it will delete it from the database.
它将从数据库中删除它。
And it could cascade and delete other things as well
它也可以层叠并删除其他的东西
depending on what delete rule is, all right?
取决于删除规则是什么?
Most of the time by default, when I delete something,
默认情况下，当我删除某个东西时，
other things that point to it get that pointer set to nil.
其他的东西，指向它的指针被设置为nil。
That's the nullify delete rule.
这就是nullify删除规则。
Now, when things get deleted from the database they got
现在，当从数据库中删除它们时
sent this message first, prepare for deletion.
首先发送此消息，准备删除。
Okay, and this is a really good method.
这是一个很好的方法。
Again, in here you don't have to do anything
再一次，在这里你不需要做任何事情
to worry about the other pointers point to you
担心其他指针指向你
that's all fixed by the delete rule.
这都是由删除规则决定的。
But what if you had another field in your database?
但如果数据库中有另一个字段呢?
Back to the retweet count example again.
再次回到retweet计数示例。
Let's say I had an int somewhere in TwitterUser,
假设我在TwitterUser某处有一个int，
which counted the number of retweets
哪个数的retweets
that this twitter user had done.
这个twitter用户已经完成了。
And so if I was deleting a tweet and it happened to be
所以如果我正在删除一条推特，它恰好是
a retweet then I need to set that to be minus equal one.
一个retweet，然后我需要把它设为-等于1。
And here's the perfect place to do it.
这是一个完美的地方。
So tweet, and it's prepared for
所以推特，它已经准备好了
deletion saying whoop, I'm about to be deleted.
删除说whoop，我将被删除。
I'd better tell my Twitter user, cuz I'm a retweet,
我最好告诉我的推特用户，因为我是一个retweet，
that he needs to decrement his retweet count.
他需要减量他的retweet计数。
So you see why you would use prepare for deletion?
你明白为什么要准备删除了吗?
It's a way to kind of update other things in the database
这是在数据库中更新其他东西的一种方式
when as you're leaving the database.
当你离开数据库的时候。
All right, so that's it for deletion.
这就是删除的内容。
Next topic, querying,
下一个话题、查询
the most important piece of this whole database thing.
这是整个数据库中最重要的部分。
It's really a waste of time doing all this stuff if you're
如果你是这样的人，做这些事情真的是浪费时间
not gonna query, okay?
不会查询,好吗?
If you're not gonna make sophisticated requests for
如果你不准备提出复杂的要求
the information based on the relationships, etc.
基于关系的信息，等等。
So, to do a query the most important thing you need to
所以，要做一个查询，你需要做的最重要的事情
know is NSFetchRequest, this class NSFetchRequest.
知道是NSFetchRequest，这个类NSFetchRequest。
And NSFetchRequest encapsulates
和NSFetchRequest封装
what you want from the database.
你想从数据库中得到什么。
So let's talk about an NSFetchRequest and
我们来谈谈NSFetchRequest
how we build one.
如何构建一个。
So when we're building one,
所以当我们建造一个，
there's three important things we need to know.
有三个重要的事情我们需要知道。
One, what entity are we fetching?
第一，我们取回的是什么实体?
Because a FetchRequest can only Fetch one kind of entity.
因为FetchRequest只能获取一种实体。
You can, there's no such thing a FetchRequest that will give
你可以，没有一个FetchRequest会给出
you some tweet and some Twitter user.
你有一些推特和一些推特用户。
No, okay?
不,好吗?
A fetch always gives you all tweets or
取回总是会给你所有的推文
all Twitter users, make sense?
所有的Twitter用户都明白吗?
So that's the number one thing,
这是第一件事，
is we're gonna create the fetch request.
我们将创建fetchrequest。
And it will be a fetch request or a very specific entity.
它将是一个fetchrequest或者一个非常具体的实体。
And it will only be able to fetch those entities.
它只能取回那些实体。
The second thing is is an array of sort descriptors.
第二件事是一组排序描述符。
And why do we want this?
为什么要这样呢?
Because when we execute this fetch it's gonna come back
因为当我们执行这个取回时它会回来
as an array, okay?
作为一个数组,好吗?
All the matching tweets or
所有匹配的tweet或
Twitter user will come back in an array.
Twitter用户将返回一个数组。
And since it's an array,
因为它是一个数组，
arrays are not sets, arrays are ordered and so
数组不是集合，数组是有序的
we have specify what order the things are in the arrays.
我们已经指定了数组中的东西的顺序。
So we do that with these sort descriptors.
我们用这些描述符来做。
And finally, we just specify or what is it that we want,
最后，我们只要指定，或者我们想要的，
which tweets do we want, which Twitter users do we want and
我们想要什么推特，我们想要哪个Twitter用户
we do that with something called a predicate.
我们用一个谓词来做这个。
Okay, so let's dive in and
让我们开始吧
look at all three of these things.
看看这三件事。
This is what it looks like,
这就是它的样子，
kinda top level to create a fetch request.
可以创建一个fetchrequest。
Okay, you get a fetch request.
你得到一个fetchrequest。
You set the source descriptor and you set its predicate.
设置源描述符并设置其谓词。
So you get each of these three parts.
得到这三个部分。
So getting the fetch request is easy.
所以获取fetchrequest很简单。
We're gonna use that little static function
我们将使用这个小的静态函数
that the extension that I talked about, made for
这就是我所谈到的扩展
us called fetchRequest.
我们叫fetchRequest。
Now, this is one of the very few times when Swift
这是斯威夫特为数不多的几次
cannot infer the type of this return value.
无法推断此返回值的类型。
Should've put this in red, okay?
应该把它涂成红色?
Because it's so
因为它是如此
rare, Swift can almost always infer things.
很少，斯威夫特几乎总是能推断出事情。
But in turns out NSManagedObject
但结果是NSManagedObject
has a fetchRequest method and it returns the more generic
有fetchRequest方法并返回更通用的吗
kind of fetchRequest and so when you're getting it,
就像fetchRequest一样，当你得到它的时候，
it doesn't quite know which one you want.
它不知道你想要哪一个。
So when you ask a Tweet for
所以当你问一个推特的时候
its fetch request right here, you have to tell it did you
它的取回请求，你必须告诉它是你
want the one in Tweet not the one from its super class?
想要在推特上的那个不是它的超类吗?
All right? And so
好吧?所以
say let request equal NSFetchRequest.
假设让请求等于NSFetchRequest。
It's a generic type like array or something like that, right?
它是一个类似数组之类的泛型类型，对吧?
This is a fetch request only for Tweets.
这是只用于tweet的获取请求。
So you say NSFetchRequest =
你说NSFetchRequest  =
Tweet.fetchRequest().
Tweet.fetchRequest()。
And it knows, of course,
它当然知道，
that the only one that returns an NSFetchRequest for
这是唯一返回NSFetchRequest的
tweets is the fetchRequest, and that's Tweet extension.
tweets是fetchRequest，这是Tweet扩展。
So now, you have a fetchRequest,
现在，你有一个fetchRequest，
this is how you get a fetch request- couldn't be easier.
这就是获取获取请求的方法——不太容易。
You just have to remember to do that static
你只需要记住做静态的
typing right there.
打字在这里。
Okay, now we need the sortDescriptor, right?
好的，现在我们需要sortDescriptor，对吧?
It's got this array coming back.
这个数组回来了。
What order are they going to be?
他们将会是什么顺序?
SortDescriptor looks like this.
SortDescriptor看起来是这样的。
You create it with a key.
你用一个键来创建它。
That is the key, the attribute in
这就是关键所在
the database that you want to sort on, so the screen name or
你想要排序的数据库，所以是屏幕名称
even the text in the tweet or the actual name of
甚至是推特上的文字或真实的名字
the tweeter, whatever it's gonna be.
推特，不管它是什么。
This right here, sortDescriptor,
这里,sortDescriptor,
will be a sort descriptor only suitable for fetching Twitter
只适合于获取Twitter的排序描述符吗
users, because screenName is a key in Twitter user,
用户，因为屏幕名是推特用户的关键，
not in tweet, so we're gonna use this SortDescriptor
不是在推特上，所以我们要用这个SortDescriptor
in a tweet request.
在推特请求。
And I say that because on the previous slide,
我这么说是因为在之前的幻灯片上，
I just showed you how to make a fetch request for a tweet.
我刚刚向你展示了如何为一条tweet制作一个fetchrequest。
Anyway, I should just, that should have been Twitter user.
不管怎样，我应该，应该是推特用户。
But anyway, so this is a Twitter user.
不管怎样，这是一个推特用户。
SortDescriptor.
SortDescriptor。
And notice it has ascending or descending like us A to Z or
注意它上升或下降就像我们A到Z
Z to A and then it has this argument selector and
Z到A然后它有这个参数选择器
this one creates some confusion.
这造成了一些混乱。
But really this selector just says,
但这个选择器说，
what method am I gonna use to compare items to do the sort.
我将用什么方法来比较这些项。
All right now, you don't even have to specify the selector
现在，你甚至不需要指定选择器
if you don't want to and for
如果你不想这么做
almost all data types, numbers,
几乎所有的数据类型，数字，
dates, it's going to use a method called compare, okay.
日期，它将使用一个叫做compare的方法。
Compare returns something called a comparison result
比较返回的东西称为比较结果
which is either, it's the same, it's greater than, or
哪一个，它是一样的，它大于，还是
it's less than.
它小于。
So, that's what this compare method does.
这就是比较方法的作用。
And it's implemented by date.
它是按日期执行的。
It's implemented by Int32.
它是由Int32实现。
It's implemented by double.
它是由双实现。
It's even implemented by string.
它甚至用字符串来实现。
Okay? So,
好吧?所以,
you could just use compare.
你可以用比较。
But, for strings.
但是,对于字符串。
You wanna think a little bit about what kind
你想多想想哪类
of comparison do you want?
你想要什么比较?
Do you want case-insensitive compare?
您需要不区分大小写的比较吗?
Or you could even use this special compare,
或者你可以用这个特殊的比较，
called localizedStandardCompare.
叫localizedStandardCompare。
This will compare them so
这将比较它们
that it is sourced just like the finder on the Mac.
它的来源就像在Mac上的finder。
And what does the finder on the Mac do that's different
而在Mac上的取景器有什么不同呢
than case insensitive?
比不区分大小写吗?
Well, there's a lot of issues with things like diacritic
嗯，有很多问题，比如diacritic
marks, and you know,
是,你知道,
things in your local language where things sort differently,
在你当地的语言中，事情的排序方式不同，
depending on what language you're in, what locale it is.
取决于你所使用的语言，它是什么语言环境。
You'd, you sometimes you ignore the diacritics,
有时候你忽略了音符，
like accent marks.
像重音符号。
Sometimes they mean something.
有时他们意味着什么。
And, so localized standard compare is a special compare
而且，本地化的标准比较是一个特殊的比较
for strings, that knows how to do that, okay?
对于字符串，它知道怎么做，对吧?
And this is very commonly the one we will use for strings.
这是我们经常用到的字符串。
When we're gonna show something in our UI,
当我们在UI中显示一些东西时，
maybe this array of thing for fetching,
也许这一系列的抓取，
we're gonna put it in the UI.
我们把它放到UI中。
We would want it to be in order,
我们希望它是有序的，
this localizedStandardCompare.
这localizedStandardCompare。
You notice that it's an NSString dot method.
注意到它是NSString。
It's not String.localizedStandardComp-
这不是String.localizedStandardComp -
that's because this has to be an Objective-C visible method.
这是因为它必须是一个objective - c可见的方法。
are. And
是这样的。和
And you need the NSString version.
你需要NSString版本。
So basically you're going to say NSString dot, and
所以基本上你会说NSString
you can go look, search for compare in NSString or string,
你可以去找NSString或string的比较，
because a string implements them all as well but
因为一个字符串也实现了它们
you need NSString dot and then the name of the method.
你需要NSString点和方法名。
And you can search, and there is case insensitive and
你可以搜索，不区分大小写
the standard compare and then the regular compare and etc.
标准比较，然后是常规比较等。
Now one other thing about this is that,
另一个问题是，
these methods some of them are special in that,
这些方法有些很特别，
it does to compare on the database side, okay.
它可以在数据库方面进行比较。
Using SQL to do it, see what I'm saying?
使用SQL来完成它，明白我的意思吗?
It's not actually bringing all the data over.
它并没有把所有的数据都带过来。
Calling this method on every string, and
在每个字符串上调用此方法
doing some kind of quicksort or something.
做一些快速排序。
It's using super powerful sorting mechanisms that
它使用了非常强大的排序机制
are built into an SQL database, okay.
被构建到一个SQL数据库中。
So, in fact, all of the NSString ones will do that.
实际上，所有的NSString都会这样做。
Okay, so they're super duper efficient.
好吧，他们是超级高效的。
Now, if you wanted to use your own compare though,
现在，如果你想用自己的比较，
it's not gonna be efficient.
这样做效率不高。
Because it is gonna have to
因为这是必须的
bring all the data from the database into your memory so
将数据库中的所有数据都放到内存中
it can run your little method over it.
它可以在上面运行你的小方法。
So I strongly recommend
所以我强烈推荐
against using your own selector here.
不要使用你自己的选择器。
I would use the standard selectors.
我将使用标准选择器。
If you're gonna use your own selector
如果你要使用你自己的选择器
it's gotta be on a pretty small dataset.
它必须在一个很小的数据集上。
Cuz it's not gonna be very efficient.
因为这不是很有效率。
Notice that when we do the fetch request,
请注意，当我们执行取回请求时，
we don't just give it a sort descriptor,
我们不只是给它排序描述符，
we give it an array of sort descriptors.
我们给它一个排序描述符数组。
That's the old sort by last name, and then first name.
这是姓氏的旧排序，然后是名字。
Right? So if
对吧?因此,如果
we have 12 Smiths in there, we'll sort them and
我们有12个Smiths，我们会对它们排序
the Smiths will be in the right spot.
史密斯一家将会处于正确的位置。
And then all of the first names of the Smiths
然后是Smiths的所有名字
will be in order by that.
会按这个顺序排列的。
So we can have as many of these sub sort by the one
所以我们可以有很多这样的子排序
thing, sub sort by the next thing,
下一件事，
sub sort by the next thing.
下一件事。
Basically, we can break ties with subsequent sorting and
基本上，我们可以中断与后续排序的联系
that's why we give an array of sort descriptors.
这就是为什么我们给出排序描述符数组的原因。
Okay, so, that's the fetch request and
这是fetchrequest
its sort descriptors and now the predicate.
它的排序描述符和谓词。
Okay, the predicate is the guts of saying which tweets do
这个谓词是推文的核心
we want.
我们想要的。
Which Twitter users do we want?
我们想要哪个Twitter用户?
We create them with kind of interesting API.
我们用有趣的API创建它们。
It looks a lot like printf from C.
它看起来很像来自C的printf。
NSPredicate format colon, and then a string.
NSPredicate格式冒号，然后是字符串。
And the string is a format string.
字符串是一个格式字符串。
And again, looks a lot like printf.
再一次，看起来很像printf。
So the best way to explain this is probably by example.
所以最好的解释就是通过例子。
But the way you're gonna learn this is you're gonna go
但你要知道的是，你要走了
read the documentation for NSPredicate, you've got to go
读一下NSPredicate的文档，你就得走了
read that documentation, in its class documentation,
阅读文档，在它的类文档中，
there's gonna be a link that says, creating predicates,
会有一个链接，创建谓词，
or something like that, click on that, and go there, and
或者类似的东西，点击那个，然后去那里
learn all the things you can put in this format string,
学习所有你可以放入这个格式字符串的东西，
cuz it's all very specific to doing database queries, but
因为这都是针对数据库查询的，但是
I'll show you some examples, so
我会给你们看一些例子
you get an idea of what's going on here.
你知道这里发生了什么。
So here's the first one,
这是第一个，
let's have the search string called foo.
让我们有一个名为foo的搜索字符串。
All these searches then I'm gonna do right here
所有这些搜索，我就在这里做
are tweet searches.
微博搜索。
These are for predicates for searching for a tweet.
这些是用于搜索tweet的谓词。
So first, I'm gonna find all the tweets whose text,
首先，我要找到所有的推文，
the actual tweet, the 140 characters of pure joy or
真正的推特，140个纯粹的快乐
whatever, contains case sensitive.
无论如何,包含大小写敏感的。
Case insensitively.
区分大小写。
That's what [c] means.
这就是[c]的意思。
%@. %@ is a substitution variable,
and I have to give its value at the end.
最后我要给出它的值。
And so I'm substituting search string.
我在用搜索字符串替换。
Okay, note that I can't say, text contains foo.
注意，我不能说，文本包含foo。
I have to say, text contains %@ and then.
我不得不说，文本包含% @，然后。
Put something at the end there.
把东西放到最后。
Okay, so that's an obvious one,
这很明显，
I'm searching for all my tweets that contain foo.
我正在搜索所有包含foo的tweet。
How about this one?
这一个怎么样?
I want all the tweets whose tweeter equals %@.
我想要所有推特都是% @的推文。
I'm going to put Joe in there as the substitution variable
我把Joe放到这里作为替换变量
and created after some date that I create.
并在我创建的某个日期后创建。
See that? I'm using greater
看到了吗?我用大
than to do that.
比。
And I'm doing && for and,
我在做& &，
you can also use the word and there.
你也可以用这个词。
Okay? So that's all gonna be
好吧?这就是全部
the tweets created by Joe since that date.
乔自那一天起创建的推文。
You're starting to see the power of building the query
您已经看到了构建查询的能力
into the database, right?
到数据库中,对吧?
If I had thousands of tweets, it'd be really easy to find
如果我有成千上万条推文，很容易找到
the ones since yesterday, for example.
例如，从昨天开始。
I'll show you that in a second here.
我马上会给你们看。
Aand then I can also though, search through dot notation,
然后我还可以通过点符号来搜索，
on other fields, in other entities, but
在其他领域，在其他实体中，但是
this tweeter.screenName equals percent @ sign%@ with CS193P,
这个推特。在CS193P中，screenName = % @ @ % @ @ @ @ @，
that's still searching for tweets.
这还在搜索推文。
That's searching for
这是寻找
tweets whose tweeter's screen name is CS193P.
推特的屏幕名称是CS193P的推文。
Do you see what it's doing there?
你看到它在那里做什么了吗?
This is still a tweet predicate.
这仍然是一个tweet谓词。
This is not a twitter user predicate.
这不是一个twitter用户谓词。
Okay?
好吧?
So here's a different predicate.
这是一个不同的谓词。
This one is for Twitter user.
这个是给Twitter用户的。
So here I'm searching for all the Twitter users
我在搜索所有的推特用户
Okay?
好吧?
who has a Tweet whose text contains foo.
谁有一条含有foo的Tweet。
Okay?
好吧?
So it even knows how to do a pluralistic
所以它甚至知道如何做多元的
search right here where you've got tweets dot text that means
在这里搜索，你会得到tweets。text
all the tweets, texts and doing contains and
所有的推文，文本和做的都包含和
we can do [c] if we wanted foo.
如果我们想要，我们可以做。
So that's a twitter user search right there.
这就是twitter用户搜索。
the twitter users who have tweeted anything that includes
推特用户在推特上发布了任何内容
We're looking for
我们正在寻找
foo, again a powerful search, really easy to express.
foo，再一次强大的搜索，很容易表达。
Question.
的问题。
>> [INAUDIBLE] >> So the question,
does it infer this from the name of the variable,
它是从变量的名字推导出来的，
it's not inferring it,
这不是推断,
it's actually using the name of the attribute tweets
它实际上是在使用属性tweets的名称
right there and the name of the attribute text and it's
这里和属性文本的名称
building a SQL statement that will go and do this fetch.
构建一个SQL语句，然后执行这个fetch。
Okay now it's doing all that underneath the covers,
现在它在覆盖范围内做所有的事情，
we don't care how, but it's doing it.
我们不关心怎么做，但它就是这么做的。
Yeah, compound predicate.
是的,复合谓语。
You can build a compound predicate like an and
您可以构建一个复合谓词，像an和
predicate or an or predicate.
谓词或谓词。
You could put or or and in the string, or
你可以把它放在弦里，或者
you could create separate predicates and and
您可以创建独立的谓词和
them together by creating an NSCompoundPredicate.
它们通过创建一个nscompound谓词在一起。
And predicate with sub-predicates, and
谓词与子谓词，以及
just given an array of predicates and
只要给出一个谓词数组
it ands them together.
它and在一起。
Why would you ever want to do this versus just putting and
你为什么要这么做，而不是仅仅投入
or, or in there?
或者,还是在那里?
Well, maybe you're computing what the predicates are,
也许你在计算谓词是什么，
based on some, depending on what the user clicked on or
基于一些，取决于用户点击的是什么
something, you're computing it, and
你在计算它
so you want to add these things you computed together.
你想把这些相加。
All right, there's also function predicates.
好的，还有函数谓词。
Now these are super powerful predicates,
这些都是非常强大的谓词，
and you don't need these for your homework, so
你不需要这些来做作业
don't worry too much about these, but they're cool.
不要太担心这些，但它们很酷。
You can even say, you have a search like this one,
你甚至可以说，像这样的搜索，
tweets.@count > 5,
tweet。@count > 5,
this is a Twitter user search, that finds
这是一个Twitter用户搜索
all the Twitter users who have more than 5 Tweets, okay?
所有的推特用户都有5条以上的推文，对吧?
So, @count is actually running, kind of a function in
@ count实际上是在运行一个函数
the database, to go count the number of Tweets that
数据库，来计算推文的数量
the Twitter user has.
Twitter用户。
So, again, you'll see all of this when you go look at
再一次，你会看到所有这些
the NSPredicate documentation, it's incredibly powerful,
NSPredicate文档，非常强大，
you can see you barely have to type anything in as the format
您可以看到，您几乎不需要键入任何内容作为格式
string, and you get these really powerful searches.
字符串，你得到这些非常强大的搜索。
All right, so let's put it all together now to create
好了，让我们把它放到一起来创建
our fetch request, okay.
我们获取的请求。
I'm gonna create,
我要创建、
in this case, a Twitter user fetch request.
在本例中，是一个Twitter用户获取请求。
So I'm saying a FetchRequest =
我说的是FetchRequest  =
TwitterUser.fetchRequest(), then I'm gonna
TwitterUser.fetchRequest(),然后我要
create a time which was yesterday,
创造一个昨天，
it's actually not, it's 24 hours ago.
实际上不是，24小时前。
Time interval since now, minus 24 times 60 times 60,
从现在开始的时间间隔，减去24乘以60乘以60，
that's 24 hours ago, and I'm creating a predicate
那是24小时前，我在创建一个谓词
that says, find me any Twitter users that have a Tweet that's
也就是说，找到任何有推特的推特用户
created before yesterday, or since yesterday I guess,
在昨天之前，或者从昨天开始，
yes, created is greater than yesterday.
是的，创造比昨天大。
So I'm finding all the Twitter users who have created Tweets
所以我找到所有创建推特的推特用户
in the last twenty-four hours, that's what this one does.
在过去的24小时里，这就是这个。
So any is a special term that means match any
所以任何一个都是一个特殊的术语，意思是和任何一个
of these things, and
这些东西,
these things are Tweets that are created since yesterday.
这些是自昨天以来创建的tweet。
And I'm gonna sort the result by the actual name,
我要用实际的名字排序，
the real name of the Twitter user.
Twitter用户的真实姓名。
So I'm just doing sortDescriptor, key of name,
我在做sortDescriptor,name的键，
ascending true, I'm not specifying a selector, so
提升为真，我没有指定选择器
I'm gonna get kind of the default comparison.
我会得到默认的比较。
Okay, that's it, so that's how you create a fetch request.
这就是创建fetchrequest的方法。
Now, since I have a fetch request, how do I make it go?
既然我有一个fetchrequest，那我该怎么做呢?
Give me those Tweets, give me those Twitter users.
给我那些推文，给我推特用户。
We do that with the very simple method in context, so
我们用非常简单的方法来做，所以
we ask the context to do the fetch, and it will go out and
我们要求context做取回，然后它就会出来
return an array of all those things,
返回所有这些东西的数组，
sorted in the way the fetch request says to sort them.
按照获取请求的方式对它们进行排序。
Okay, simple as that.
好了,就这么简单。
The only thing not so simple, it throws, okay?
唯一没有这么简单的东西，它抛出，对吧?
Just like context save throws, context execute also throws.
就像上下文保存抛出，上下文执行也抛出。
So, you could put in a try question mark,
你可以用一个问号，
in that case, if the execute fails, and usually it's gonna
在这种情况下，如果执行失败，通常它会
fail because your predicate is wrong, or something.
因为你的谓词错了，或者别的什么。
Like your predicate just makes no sense then you could fail.
就像你的谓词没有意义那样你就会失败。
If it's gonna fail, you're gonna get back nil,
如果它失败了，你会返回nil，
if you do try question mark,
如果你尝试问号，
remember that's what try question mark means.
记住，这就是问号的意思。
It means try this, and if it fails, give back nil.
它的意思是尝试这个，如果失败了，就返回nil。
But it if doesn't fail,
但如果没有失败，
then you're gonna get an optional array.
然后你会得到一个可选的数组。
And that array is gonna be empty,
这个数组是空的，
if it couldn't find anything that matches your request, or,
如果它找不到符合你要求的东西，
it's gonna be full of objects, okay?
会有很多对象?
Tweets, or Twitter users, an array of tweets, or
推文、推特用户、推文数组或
an array of Twitter users,
一群推特用户，
at least that's what it's gonna look like to you,
至少这是它看起来的样子，
it's not quite that, looks like it, all right?
看起来不太像，对吧?
That's the result you're gonna get back, so, again,
这就是你要回来的结果，
super simple querying.
超级简单的查询。
Now, you might be a little scared of doing this request,
现在，你可能有点害怕做这个请求，
what if it's matches a million things, okay?
如果匹配一百万件呢?
Are you gonna get a million Tweets back in one
你会收到一百万条回复吗
request like this?
这样的请求吗?
The answer is no.
答案是否定的。
This array that you get back is really super smart array.
你返回的这个数组非常智能。
It doesn't actually bring the data in from the database,
它实际上并没有从数据库中获取数据，
until you start asking for it, okay?
在你开始要求之前，好吗?
So until I ask for the Twitter user,
在我问推特用户之前，
a certain Twitter user's information,
一个特定的Twitter用户的信息，
the Twitter user's name, the Twitter user's screen name,
推特用户的名字，推特用户的屏幕名，
the Twitter user did not get faulted from the database.
Twitter用户没有从数据库中出错。
This is called faulting, okay?
这叫做断层作用?
And so, these objects, you can imagine,
这些物体，你可以想象，
they're kind of shells, empty shells.
它们是贝壳，空壳。
And until you crack open the shell and
直到你打开壳
start looking inside,
开始在里面,
it doesn't actually get the data for you.
它实际上并没有为你获取数据。
And the reason this matters to you is,
这对你来说很重要，
if you go in the debugger, or you do a print statement,
如果你进入调试器，或者你做一个打印声明，
like this one where you say, for user in recentTweeters
就像你说的这个，用户在最近的推特
fetched user whatever, when you print that out,
当你把它打印出来的时候，
it's not gonna print the, a Tweeter user object,
它不会打印，Tweeter用户对象，
it's gonna print some kind of faulting shel.
它会打印出一些错误的shel。
Because you haven't actually asked for
因为你还没有要求
any of the data inside that thing yet, so
里面有任何数据
it hasn't faulted yet.
它还没有断裂。
But if you say, for
但如果你说，因为
user in recentTweeters and say fetched user named, and
用户在最近的tweeter和说获取的用户名，和
now you say user.name, now you are faulting this object in.
现在你说user。name，现在你在把这个对象错了。
In fact, this for
事实上,这
loop would fault all these objects in to memory.
loop将把所有这些对象都记在内存中。
Okay, fetch them all, cuz you're asking for
好吧，把它们都拿来，因为你要的
the name of every single one.
每个人的名字。
Boom, fault, fault, fault, they're all coming in.
砰，错，错，错，他们都进来了。
Now, it doesn't do it one by one, it faults in batches,
它不是一个接一个地做，而是分批处理，
it's really high performance, so,
它的性能很好，
you know, don't worry about that.
你知道，别担心。
But just, I just don't want you to be surprised
但是，我只是不想让你感到惊讶
when you go in the debugger and
当你进入调试器和
you're like, I printed out this Twitter, user and
你就像，我打印了这个推特，用户和
there's no screen name, what's going on?
没有屏幕名称，发生了什么?
Well, it hasn't faulted it in.
它没有断裂。
In fact, the debugger you could say,
实际上，调试器你可以说，
print the user.name,
打印user.name,
and it would fault it in, okay, give it to you.
它会对你造成错误，好的，给你。
All right, I told you I was gonna talk about Core Data
好吧，我告诉过你我会讲到Core Data
thread safety, so here it is.
线程安全，这里。
NSManagedObjectContext, the context thing,
NSManagedObjectContext,上下文的事情,
that thing that you're sending executes to,
你发送的那个东西会被执行，
that thing that you're hitting save, the things that you're
那就是你正在努力拯救的东西，你所拥有的东西
using to create Tweet, Tweet, subcontext,
使用创建Tweet,Tweet，子上下文，
colon whatever, that handle on database is not thread safe.
无论如何，数据库的处理不是线程安全的。
A context can only be used on the queue
上下文只能在队列上使用
that it was created on, period.
它是在一段时间内创造出来的。
If you past a context to another queue,
如果你经过一个context到另一个队列，
like you tried to dispatch off to some
就像你试图向一些人发送
global concurrent queue, and you pasted the context, or
全局并发队列，您粘贴了上下文，或者
even just pasted a Tweet, okay, that's not gonna work,
即使只是贴了一条推文，也不会起作用，
cuz that Tweet was created on this other context.
这条推特是在另一个背景下创建的。
So in fact, not only the context,
所以事实上，不仅是背景，
but everything that you create on that context
但你在这方面所创造的一切
has to all be done in the same queue.
必须在相同的队列中完成。
So now you're probably thinking,
现在你可能在想，
well how the heck do I do multithreading then?
那我到底怎么做多线程呢?
Cuz a database especially, you can imagine, for
尤其是数据库，你可以想象
temple one to load your database off the main queue,
temple one将你的数据库加载到主队列，
cuz you, you might be loading lots and lots of things.
因为你，你可能正在装载很多东西。
Now your queries,
现在你的查询,
your probably gonna do those on the main queue because,
你可能会在主队列上做这些，
the user's looking at that information.
用户正在查看这些信息。
You want it to be highly responsive.
你希望它反应灵敏。
Okay, it's probably worth, and core data is super fast,
很可能，核心数据非常快，
especially with queries.
尤其是在查询。
So, you could probably do that on the main queue.
你可以在主队列上做。
But loading it up,
但加载它,
you probably don't want to do that.
你可能不想这么做。
All right, so, how do we do multithreading?
好，那么，我们怎么做多线程呢?
Although that we do multithreading in Core Data,
虽然我们在Core Data中做多线程，
is each database can have multiple contexts, okay?
每个数据库都可以有多个上下文，对吗?
So, the database underneath, is multithreaded,
下面的数据库是多线程的，
it can have multiple contexts writing to it.
它可以有多个上下文写入它。
Okay, completely different context,
好的,完全不同的背景下,
writing to the same database, in different queue's even, so
写入相同的数据库，在不同的队列中，甚至
it's fully multithreaded.
它是完全多线程。
So that means we had to have a context for every queue.
这意味着我们必须为每个队列都有一个context。
Whatever queue we're going to access the database,
不管我们要访问哪个队列，
we have to a context in every queue.
我们必须在每个队列中都有一个上下文。
Now I'm gonna show you how to create a context, or
现在，我将向您展示如何创建上下文，或者
on another queue, so
另一个队列,因此
you can do something with that queue in a second here.
你可以在这个队列中做一些事情。
But first I want to talk about this important
但首先我想谈谈这个重要的事情
method in context called performBlock.
在上下文中的方法称为performBlock。
performBlock just takes a closure,
performBlock只需要关闭，
a closure that takes no arguments,
一个没有参数的闭包，
returns no arguments, and it will ensure, this is
不返回任何参数，它将确保这是
an insurance method, it will ensure that everything inside
一种保险方法，它能保证里面的一切
that closure happens on the right queue for that context.
该闭包发生在该上下文的正确队列上。
Okay, so this, don't get confused,
好的，这个，不要搞混了，
this method does not dispatch, you know,
这个方法不会发送，你知道，
cause background thrading, this is just making sure that,
因为背景色，这是为了确保，
that closure executes on the right queue.
该闭包在正确的队列上执行。
So this is a way that you can kind of be safe.
这是一种安全的方法。
And some might argue you should put performBlock around
有些人可能会说，你应该把performBlock放在周围
every single call to every Core Data thing you ever do,
每个呼叫到你做过的每一个核心数据，
because that will ensure that you'll never have a problem
因为那将确保你永远不会有问题
where you're accessing the context not on it's queue.
访问上下文而不是队列。
Okay, it accidentally, you got some bad code.
不小心，你有一些坏代码。
Now, that might be a little bit overkill especially if
现在，这可能有点过分了，尤其是
you're mostly using the main queue anyway, and
不管怎样，你基本上都在使用主队列
you really, maybe you only use background queues for
实际上，您可能只使用后台队列
this tiny little bit of processing on the side.
这个小一点的处理。
It's not like you have the tons context and
它不像你有大量的上下文
lots of different queues all going at each other.
许多不同的队列都在互相攻击。
So, it might be overkill.
所以，它可能是过量的。
But if you're doing anything where you have,
但如果你在做任何事情，
truly have multiple context on multiple queues and
在多个队列中确实有多个上下文
they're access and things, this is a good way to be safe.
他们是有机会的，这是一个安全的好方法。
Okay, so all this does is it makes it so you are safe.
好了，所有这些都是为了让你安全。
The code inside that block will be executed on the proper
该块中的代码将在适当的地方执行
queue for that context.
队列上下文。
Even if it has to dispatch, it will do it if it has to.
即使它必须分派，它也会做如果它必须。
If it doesn't have to dispatch,
如果不需要分派，
if you're on the right queue, it'll just execute it, fine.
如果你在正确的队列上，它就会执行它，很好。
But if you're on the wrong queue right now and
但如果你现在排错队了
you execute this,
你执行这个,
it will dispatch it to the right queue.
它将把它发送到正确的队列。
There's also performBlockAndWait,
还有performBlockAndWait,
which will get it on the right queue and
哪一个会把它放在正确的队列上
wait until it's done, and then continue in your queue.
等待它完成，然后继续在您的队列中。
Okay, but this doesn't really talk about,
但这并不是真正的讨论，
how do I get another context in a different thread, right?
如何在不同的线程中获取另一个上下文?
I wanna do some code on another thread.
我想在另一个线程上做一些代码。
Where do I get a context?
我从哪里得到上下文?
The only context I know how to get right now is viewContext.
我所知道的唯一的上下文是viewContext。
That's the main queue's context,
这是主队列的上下文，
that's the only only one I can get.
这是我唯一能得到的。
Okay, well, you're gonna use this really cool method
好吧，你要用这个很酷的方法
in persistentContainer.
在persistentContainer。
This is new in iOS 10 and a really cool method,
这是iOS 10中的新方法，非常酷的方法，
super cool.
超级酷。
It makes it really easy to do background process on
这使得做后台处理很容易
Core Data.
核心数据。
It's called performBackgroundTask.
它叫做performBackgroundTask。
Remember, this is a function on persistentContainer that
记住，这是一个关于persistentContainer的函数
you get from the AppDelegate.
从AppDelegate获得。
And this takes a closure.
这需要关闭。
This closure has one argument, the argument is a context.
这个闭包有一个参数，参数是上下文。
And that context is appropriate for use
这个上下文适合使用
on this other thread that this is going to create for you.
在另一个线程上，它将为你创建。
So this performBackgroundTask finds another queue,
这个performBackgroundTask找到另一个队列，
not the main queue, some other queue.
不是主队列，也不是其他队列。
And it creates a context in that other queue, and it
它在另一个队列中创建了一个上下文
executes your closure on that other queue in the background.
在后台的另一个队列上执行闭包。
Now, it's a convenience method.
现在，这是一个方便的方法。
So if you really needed to control the quality of
所以如果你真的需要控制质量
service, for example, the queue and all the, okay, well,
服务，例如，队列和所有的，好的，
you can't use this.
你不能使用这个。
But 99.99% of the time, whatever quality of
但是99.99%的时间，无论质量如何
service that queue is getting is the right one for
队列的服务是正确的
Core Data cuz Core Data knows its business.
Core Data cuz Core Data知道它的业务。
So you're gonna do it.
所以你要去做。
Now, inside this closure couple of things really
现在，在这关闭的几件事里面
be careful of.
小心的。
One, never use viewContext in here.
第一，不要在这里使用viewContext。
Do you see why that would be horrendously bad to
你知道为什么那是可怕的坏事吗
use viewContext inside this closure?
在这个闭包中使用viewContext ?
Because this closure by definition is not executing on
因为这个定义没有执行
the main queue.
主要的队列。
By definition this closure is on a separate
根据定义，这个闭包是独立的
queue on a background queue.
在后台队列上排队。
That's the whole point of this thing,
这就是问题的关键，
is to put this thing on another queue.
就是把这个放到另一个队列上。
So never use viewContext in there,
不要使用viewContext，
that's why it's in red, okay?
这就是为什么它是红色的?
The second thing is don't forget to save this context.
第二件事是别忘了保存这个上下文。
If you do a whole bunch of stuff in here and
如果你在这里做一大堆东西
you don't save, you just did for
你不存钱，你只是做了
nothing cuz you did in memory.
没有你在记忆中做过的事。
And then this block went away, you're never gonna get that
然后这个块消失了，你永远不会得到它
context back again, that data is lost.
上下文又回来了，数据丢失了。
Which all gonna leave the heap and then nothing ever happens.
所有这些都会离开堆，然后什么也没有发生。
It never gonna get committed to the database.
它永远不会提交到数据库。
So, don't forget to save before you leave.
所以，在你离开之前别忘了存钱。
Now, when you save,
现在,当你保存,
it will push it down to the database and
它会把它推到数据库
your other context like your viewContext will see it, okay?
你的其他背景，比如你的viewContext会看到它，对吧?
And so these two contexts, the one that's happening on this
所以这两种情况，发生在这
background and the viewContext.
背景和viewContext。
They're working on the same database, so
他们在同一个数据库上工作
when this one saves,
当这一保存,
boom this guys is gonna start seeing those changes.
嘣，这家伙就会看到这些变化。
I'm gonna talk a little bit how react to seeing those
我要讲一下看到这些的反应
changes in a minute here.
这里有一分钟的变化。
Okay, so, everyone understand this?
大家都明白了吗?
Cuz you're gonna have to do this in assignment five.
因为你必须在作业5中做这个。
And I want you to do all your loading off the main queue,
我要你把所有的加载都从主队列出来，
and all your fetching on the main queue.
以及你在主队列上的所有取回。
All right, Core Data is huge.
好的，Core Data是巨大的。
Huge.
巨大的。
I can't cover it all.
我不能全包住。
It's got optimistic locking, for
这是一个乐观的锁定
those of you that know about database.
那些了解数据库的人。
It's got optimistic locking and all that database stuff.
它有乐观锁定和所有数据库内容。
It has full undo, redo, which is incredible.
它有完全的撤销，重做，这是令人难以置信的。
It obviously knows how to roll back unsaved changes.
它显然知道如何回滚未保存的更改。
Okay, if you have changes in memory and
好的，如果你的记忆发生了变化
you want to roll some of them back,
你想把它们卷回去，
you can do that before you save.
在你存钱之前你可以这样做。
It knows about staleness, like, if I make a fetch,
它知道什么是过时，比如，如果我做一个取回，
how long before I really wanna fetch it again because I don't
在我真正想要取回它之前多久，因为我没有
trust that the data hasn't changed, right?
相信数据没有改变，对吧?
How long it takes for the data to get stale.
数据要多久才会失效。
And a lot of other things in the Core Data.
Core Data中还有很多其他的东西。
So, I can't cover it all,
所以，我无法涵盖所有的内容，
there's not enough time to do that.
没有足够的时间去做。
Cuz we're trying to talk about a whole another topic about
因为我们正试着讨论另一个话题
But you'll want to check the documentation, you won't need
但是您需要检查文档，您不需要
Core Data here.
核心数据。
anything else of this stuff to do your homeworks, of course,
当然，还有其他的东西可以做作业，
I'm just trying to get you started with this.
我只是想让你从这个开始。
But you need to know that this stuff is in there, so that
但是你需要知道这些东西在里面，所以
one day when you go out and do some significant iOS database
有一天当你出去做一些重要的iOS数据库时
stuff, you'll know that these features are out there.
东西，你会知道这些功能在外面。
All right, the next topic here is Core Data and UITableView.
好，下一个主题是Core Data和UITableView。
As you can imagine, this is a marriage made in heaven, okay?
你们可以想象，这是一个在天堂里制造的婚姻，对吧?
Because you got this database,
因为你有了这个数据库，
got all this big data sets in there and
所有这些大数据集都在这里
what is the UI we use to show big data sets in iOS?
我们在iOS中显示大数据集的UI是什么?
UITableView.
UITableView。
Okay, UITableView is great at showing arbitrary large
UITableView很擅长显示任意大小
data sets in our arbitrary UIs, right?
数据集在任意的ui中?
We can do custom table view cell,
我们可以做自定义表格视图单元格，
we can do anything UI we want.
我们可以做任何想要的UI。
So, this is so common that Apple has invented this very
所以，这是很常见的，苹果公司发明了这个
important class called NSFetchedResultsController.
重要的类称为NSFetchedResultsController。
This is not a viewController, okay?
这不是一个viewController ?
This is a controller that controls Core Data and
这是一个控制核心数据的控制器
UITableView talking together,
UITableView说在一起,
but it's not in its fetch results view controller, okay?
但它不是在它的fetchedresultsviewcontroller中，对吧?
And all this NSFetchedResultsController
所有这些NSFetchedResultsController
does is it hooks up an NSFetchRequest that you create
它是否与您创建的NSFetchRequest挂钩
to a UITableView.
UITableView。
And it hooks them up in such a strong way that if anything
它以一种强有力的方式将它们连接起来
changes in the database that would cause that fetch request
数据库中的更改将导致获取请求
to return different results, it updates the table
为了返回不同的结果，它更新了表格
automatically, you don't have to do anything.
自动地，你不需要做任何事情。
So this is an active live hookup between
这是一个活跃的活的连接
the NSFetchRequest and the TableView, okay?
NSFetchRequest和TableView ?
Even if some other context are changing the data, it doesn't
即使一些其他的上下文正在改变数据，它也没有
matter, it's always keeping that TableView up to date.
重要的是，它一直保持着这个TableView。
So I'm gonna talk about how we do this,
我要讲一下我们是怎么做的，
how we use an NSFetchedResultsController.
我们如何使用一个NSFetchedResultsController。
I'm even gonna provide you some kind of free code
我甚至会给你提供一些免费的代码
to do some of it.
做一些。
You'll have to type in a little bit of the rest of it.
你得输入一点剩下的部分。
But it's, it's pretty easy to do.
但这很容易做到。
So how fundamentally does
那么如何从根本上
NSFetchedResultsController work?
NSFetchedResultsController工作吗?
Two ways, one, it has a delegate and
有两种方法，一种是委托
that delegate you set to be your UITableViewController.
这个委托就是UITableViewController。
And whenever the FetchResultsController sees
当FetchResultsController看到
something happening
发生了一些事情
in the database that would affect that fetchRequest,
在会影响fetchRequest的数据库中，
it tells the table view controller, hey, do this,
它告诉表视图控制器，
add this row, add a section, reload this row, whatever,
添加这一行，添加一个section，重载这一行，
it uses UITableView primitives to update the table, okay?
它使用UITableView原语来更新表，对吧?
I'm gonna show you,
我要告诉你,
I'm gonna give you the code that does that part of it,
我将给你代码，
that implements the NSFetchedResultsController's
实现NSFetchedResultsController
delegate, okay, so that's one way it does it.
委托，好的，这是它的一种方式。
The other way that the NSFetchedResultsController
NSFetchedResultsController的另一种方式
works is that it provides implementation for
工作是它提供实现
all of your UITableView data sources methods, right?
所有UITableView数据源方法，对吧?
Because the contents of your table
因为你桌子的内容
are coming out of the database,
从数据库中出来，
so NSFetchedResultsController lets you know all of them, how
所以NSFetchedResultsController让你知道所有这些,怎么做
many sections, how many rows and sections all that stuff.
很多分段，有多少行和分段。
In fact, this is what it looks like,
事实上，这就是它的样子，
this is the implementation that you're gonna put in to
这是你要放入的实现
your controller when you have fetchedResultsController.
当你有,fetchedResultsController控制器。
The first thing you're gonna
你要做的第一件事
do is you're gonna create a fetchedResultsController, and
做的是你要创建一个,fetchedResultsController,
I'm gonna show you how to do that in a moment.
我一会儿会告诉你们怎么做。
And so you're always gonna have a var called
所以你总是会调用一个var
fetchedResultsController, and
,fetchedResultsController,
it's gonna be of type NSFetchedResultsController.
它会NSFetchedResultsController类型。
And when you have that var, now you can implement your
当你有了这个var，现在你可以实现你的
sections, number of sections in TableView by saying return
分段，在TableView中，通过返回来表示
fetchedResultsController .sections.count, okay?
,fetchedResultsController .sections。数,好吗?
Those are a lot of optionals in there, so
那里有很多选择，所以
we'll default to one section.
我们将默认为一个部分。
And then to get the number of rows in a section,
然后为了得到section中的行数，
you're just gonna say the,
你只是想说，
you're gonna get the sections first by saying
你会先说
fetchedResultsController?.sec- tions.
,fetchedResultsController ?。秒,。
And as long as you have some sections, sections.count
只要你有部分，sections.count
greater than zero, then you're gonna return the sections in
大于零，然后你将返回这些部分
that section that's passed to you number of objects.
这个部分传递给你的对象数。
Okay, so that code, that's it, that's all of your, those two
好的，这就是代码，这就是你们所有的，这两个
methods, that's the entire implementation if you're using
方法，如果使用的话，这就是整个实现
a fetchedResultsController, okay?
,fetchedResultsController ?
And then of course, there's cellForRowAt, okay,
当然，还有cellForRowAt，好的，
you gotta implement that, that one too,
你也要实现这个，
you're gonna use fetchedResultsController.
你会使用,fetchedResultsController。
And the most important thing about cellForRowAt is you need
关于cellForRowAt，最重要的是你需要
to know what's at that row, which thing in my database is
要知道这一行是什么，数据库中是什么
at that row in that section in my table.
在我桌子的那一排。
And you get that by asking the fetchedResultsController with
你可以通过询问fetchedResultsController来得到它
this method objectAtIndexPath.
这种方法objectAtIndexPath。
So you just say fetchedResultsController,
你只是说,fetchedResultsController,
give me the object, and that object is gonna be a tweet, or
给我对象，那个对象将是一条tweet，或者
a Twitter user, or whatever, some entity.
一个推特用户，或者别的什么实体。
Give me an object at the index path
在索引路径上给我一个对象
that cellForRowAt indexPath is asking me for.
那个cellForRowAt indexPath正在请求我。
So now I have the Twitter user or the tweet,
现在我有了推特用户或推特，
I can easily load up my UI.
我可以轻松地加载UI。
You know, pass it off to my UI, custom UITableView cell,
你知道，把它传递给我的UI，自定义UITableView cell，
or if I have a subtitle cell,
或者如果我有一个subtitle cell，
just take a couple of things out of there and
把这些东西拿出来
put it in the text label in the detailed text label,
把它放到文本标签中，
you see what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗?
But you can see that the fetchedResultsController,
但是你可以看到,fetchedResultsController,
that code in yellow right there in the middle of
那个黄色的代码就在中间
cellForRowAt indexPath,
that's doing all the work to figure out what tweet or
这是在做所有的工作来弄清楚推特或什么
what Twitter user is at this row in the table, okay?
推特用户在表格中的这一行?
So those code on the last slide and
这是最后一张幻灯片的代码
the code on this slide, you'll have to type that code in any
这张幻灯片上的代码，你必须键入代码
time you're using an NSFetchedResultsController.
当你使用一个NSFetchedResultsController。
Now, on the previous slide, one of the things was var
在之前的幻灯片中，其中一个是var
fetchedResultsController equals something.
,fetchedResultsController =。
So now let's talk about how we create
现在我们来谈谈我们是如何创造的
a fetchedResultsController, okay?
,fetchedResultsController ?
So this is what the initializer for
这就是初始化程序
NSFetchedResultsController looks like here.
NSFetchedResultsController看起来像。
It takes a request, a context.
它需要一个请求，一个context。
Obviously, it doesn't know what database
显然，它不知道什么是数据库
we're fetching in.
我们抓取。
And then it's got a sectionNameKeyPath.
然后它有一个sectionNameKeyPath。
That sectionNameKeyPath is the var in
sectionNameKeyPath是var in
that entity that, whose value is a string,
这个实体，它的值是一个字符串，
which is the title of the section it's in, okay?
这就是它的标题，明白吗?
That's how you do sections with fetchedResultsController.
这就是你做的部分,fetchedResultsController。
You just have to, and you might have to invent this or
你只需要，你可能需要发明这个或
even calculate this.
甚至计算。
But all of your tweets or all your Twitter users, if they're
但所有的推文或推特用户，如果他们是
gonna be in sections, they all have to have a var,
在分段中，它们都有一个var，
which is a string, which is the section they're in, okay,
这是一个字符串，这是它们所在的section，好的，
the name of the section they're in.
他们所处的区域的名称。
And as long as they have that, then the fetchedResults will,
只要他们有这些，fetchedResults就会，
will make the sections and
会做这些部分吗
put them all in there in the right section.
把它们都放在右边的部分。
And we'll talk about cacheName in a second here.
我们一会儿会讲到cacheName。
So we have to create a fetchRequest to put in here.
所以我们必须创建一个fetchRequest放在这里。
So here's an example of creating a fetchRequest for
这里有一个创建fetchRequest的例子
tweets, right?
微博,对吧?
So you recognize that first line there,
你知道第一行，
creating a fetchRequest for tweets.
创建tweet的fetchRequest。
And I'm gonna sort by when the tweets were created, okay,
我要在推文创建的时候排序，
when the tweet was tweeted out.
当这条推文被推出来的时候。
And I'm gonna look for all the tweets whose tweeter's name
我要找所有推特用户名的推文
equals some name, the name, okay?
等于名字，好吗?
So it's gonna get all those tweets, and
它会得到所有这些推文
I'm gonna set that request as the first argument there,
我将把这个请求设置为第一个参数，
to NSFetchedResultsController.
NSFetchedResultsController。
By the way, notice NSFetchedResultsController is
顺便说一下,请注意NSFetchedResultsController
also a generic type, and NSFetchedResultsController can
也是一个泛型类型,NSFetchedResultsController可以
only control fetches for a certain type.
只能控制特定类型的获取。
So you have to say what type, okay, what type of entity that
你必须说出哪种类型的实体
your FetchController is doing, and these are the same type of
FetchController正在做，这些是相同类型的
things that are in the rows of your table.
你桌子上的那些东西。
Now that cacheName at the bottom is interesting.
现在，底部的cacheName很有趣。
That is actually going to permanently cache the results.
这实际上会永久地缓存结果。
it's gonna get the results out of the database and
它会从数据库中得到结果
In other words,
换句话说,
store on disk the result in some internal format.
在磁盘上存储一些内部格式的结果。
And that's cool, and that storage, by the way,
这很酷，顺便说一下，
if you quit your app and come back,
如果你退出app回来，
it will still use that cache, so it's quite efficient.
它仍然会使用缓存，所以效率很高。
But you have to be a little bit careful.
但你得小心一点。
You cannot change anything about your request.
你不能改变你的要求。
As soon as you change anything about your request, like
一旦你改变了你的要求，就像
the name, the tweeter.name that you're searching for, or
你正在搜索的名字，tweeter . name
what you're sorting by, or anything.
你在排序什么，或者其他什么。
Now that cache is invalid, and you'll have to invalidate that
现在缓存无效，您将不得不使其无效
cache, okay, and there's an API in there for doing that.
缓存，这里有一个API。
You can pass nil there if you don't wanna do the caching,
如果你不想做缓存，你可以在那里传递nil，
which for most reasonable sized datasets perfectly fine,
对于大多数合理大小的数据集，
you don't really need the caching.
您并不真正需要缓存。
But I just wanna emphasize that if you change your
但我想强调的是，如果你改变了你的
request, your cache is now invalid.
请求，您的缓存现在无效。
And about that section key thing, something to be careful
关于那部分的关键，要小心
about there, too, is that whatever your sortDescriptors
在那里，无论你的sortdescriptor是什么
say that your rows would sort in, that has to be
假设你的行是排序的，那必须是
exactly the same order that your sections was sorted in.
和你的部分排序的顺序完全相同。
In other words, the FetchedResultsController
换句话说，FetchedResultsController
doesn't know how to like move things around
不知道怎么喜欢到处移动
because they sort out of order of their sections.
因为它们的排列顺序不同。
That's why a lot of times that we're doing sections,
这就是为什么我们要做的很多次，
the first sortDescriptor will be sort by the section key
第一个sortDescriptor将按section键排序
name var, right?
var名字,对吧?
And then the second one will be sort by what we
然后第二项会根据我们的情况来排序
really wanna sort by, because we have to make sure
真的想要排序，因为我们必须确定
that our entire table is sorted in section order.
我们的整个表按节顺序排序。
You see why?
你知道为什么吗?
Cuz otherwise it's just weird,
因为这很奇怪，
things would all be in the wrong places.
一切都会在错误的地方。
So keyThatSaysWhichAttributeIsTh-
因此keyThatSaysWhichAttributeIsTh -
eSectionName has to sort in the same order as your
eSectionName必须与您的相同顺序排序
sortDescriptors.
sortDescriptors。
Okay, now, I told you that NSFetchedResultsController
好的,现在,我告诉你,NSFetchedResultsController
watches Core Data.
手表核心数据。
It sees changes happening in there, and it updates it.
它看到了发生的变化，并更新了它。
And it does that with its delegate, okay?
它和它的委托是一样的，对吧?
Its delegate wants to be the tableView,
它的委托就是tableView，
be the tableViewController, rather.
表,。
Cuz it's gonna tell the tableViewController, and
因为它会告诉tableViewController
it sends messages like this.
它发送这样的消息。
So this is a typical NSFetchedResultsController
这是一个典型的NSFetchedResultsController
delegate method.
委托的方法。
Controller did change add indexPath for change type, and
控制器确实更改了更改类型的indexPath
here's the new indexPath.
这是新的indexPath。
Okay, and these change types might be deleted or
好的，这些更改类型可能会被删除
inserted or modified or whatever.
插入或修改。
Now, you have to put the code in there that would call
现在，你必须把代码放到该调用的地方
the right methods on the tableView to get the sections
在tableView上的正确方法获取部分
inserted or deleted or rows added or whatever.
插入或删除或行添加或其他内容。
But I'm gonna give you that code for free, okay, and
但是我要给你免费的代码，好的，还有
the demo that I'm gonna do on Wednesday,
我周三要做的演示，
I'm gonna have a class called fetchedResultsTableViewContro-
我要上课叫fetchedResultsTableViewContro -
ller, which is gonna be a class.
ller，这是一个课程。
And you can make that to be the super class of your
你可以让它成为你的超类
UITableViewController.
UITableViewController。
And you'll just inherit this implementation of
你将继承这个实现
the delegate, okay?
委托,对吧?
Yes, cuz that's what I just said.
是的，因为我刚刚说过。
Okay, so when you're using core data in UITableView,
当你在UITableView中使用core data时，
the things to remember are, you're going to subclass
要记住的是，你要去子类化
fetchedResultsTableViewContro- ller,
fetchedResultsTableViewContro——噢,
the thing I'm gonna give you, so that you implement
我要给你的东西，让你实现
NSFetchedResultsController delegate.
NSFetchedResultsController委托。
You're going to add a var to your UITableViewController
你将给UITableViewController添加一个var
called fetchedResultsController, and
叫,fetchedResultsController,
you're gonna set its value to be
你要设置它的值
an NSFetchedResultsController with the fetchRequest that you
一个NSFetchedResultsController fetchRequest你
want, okay, that you want to populate your table.
想要填充表格。
Then you're gonna implement your UITableView data source
然后你将实现你的UITableView数据源
methods using fetchedResultsController var
使用,fetchedResultsController var的方法
methods, just like I showed you in the slides,
方法，就像我在幻灯片中展示的一样，
character for character,
字符的字符,
you can use the exact same things that are on the slide.
你可以用同样的东西在幻灯片上。
Okay, and then it's all gonna magically work, all you'll
好吧，然后它就会神奇地工作，你会
have to do is inside your cellForRowAt indexPath,
要做的是在你的cellForRowAt indexPath中，
you'll have the object, the tweet,
你会有对象，推特，
or the Twitter user, you just gotta load up your UI.
或者推特用户，你只需要加载你的UI。
After you have all this set up,
在你完成这些设置之后，
then you can proceed to using the fetchedResultsController
然后你可以继续使用fetchedResultsController
in your tableViewController.
在你的表中。
First thing you have to do is perform fetch on
首先你要做的是执行取回
the fetchedResultsController.
,fetchedResultsController。
That will cause it to go out and do your NSFetchRequest,
这会导致它退出并执行NSFetchRequest，
basically.
基本上。
It's not gonna pull all the data over, but
它不会把所有的数据都拉过来，而是
it's going to basically bring over, do the same thing as if
它基本上会带来，做同样的事情
you had executed the fetchRequest yourself, and
你自己执行了fetchRequest
then you're gonna wanna do tableView View.reloadData.
然后你要做tableView。reloaddata。
And that's because you want all of your datasource
这是因为你想要所有的数据源
methods to be called, and you know that we've implemented
方法被调用，你知道我们已经实现了
all of them in terms of our fetch results controller as
所有这些都是我们的fetchedresultscontroller
showed on the previous slides there.
显示在前面的幻灯片上。
And the only other thing you want to remember to do
你想要记住的唯一一件事就是
is set your fetch results controller's delegate to be
设置你的fetchedresultscontroller的委托吗
yourself and, again, we use that fetch results table view
你自己，再一次，我们使用fetchedresultstable视图
controller code that added the delegate methods for
添加了委托方法的控制器代码
the fetch results controller to the UITableView controller
fetchedresultscontroller到uitableviewcontroller
until we can do all the things that is necessary to
直到我们能做所有必要的事情
be a fetchedResultsController delegate.
是一个,fetchedResultsController委托。
And what that buys you is that anytime in the database
在数据库中任何时候都可以买到
changes that would affect the NSFetchedRequest
改变会影响NSFetchedRequest
that you wired up to your fetchedResultsController.
你连接到你的,fetchedResultsController。
Then, it will use that delegate to ask the table view
然后，它将使用该委托询问表视图
to update the rows or sections,
更新行或节，
whatever happened to change.
无论发生了什么变化。
So let me talk a little bit about what's coming up here,
让我来简单介绍一下这里的情况，
on Wednesday, I'm gonna do a big demo that shows you all of
周三，我要做一个展示你们所有人的演示
this stuff, as usual.
这个东西,像往常一样。
Assignment five is going out on Wednesday,
作业五在周三开始，
it'll be due the next Wednesday.
下个星期三到期。
It's going to be to add Core Data stuff to your Smashtag.
将核心数据添加到Smashtag中。
On Friday, very relevant section.
周五，非常相关的部分。
It's using CloudKit to do a database.
它使用CloudKit来做数据库。
Okay? Now, Core Data and CloudKit,
好吧?Core Data和CloudKit，
what, what are they, how are they related?
什么，他们是什么，他们是如何联系的?
Well, Core Data is for
Core Data就是for
doing things that you would do with a relational database,
做一些与关系数据库有关的事情，
these powerful queries and searches and things like that.
这些强大的查询，搜索等等。
Cloud Kit is, what if you wanted to have a database
云工具包是，如果你想要一个数据库
on the network, in the cloud, okay?
在网络上，在云中?
A network that's being shared between multiple people or
在多人之间共享的网络
even by a single person on multiple,
即使是一个人，
on multiple of their devices, or whatever.
在他们的多个设备上，或者别的什么。
So there quite different in the way they approach things.
所以他们对待事物的方式有很大的不同。
In Core Data, we do the schema using this visual mapper.
在Core Data中，我们使用这个可视化映射器来执行模式。
In CloudKit, it's essentially schema on the fly.
在CloudKit中，它基本上是动态的模式。
As you start saving vars,
当你开始省钱的时候，
it starts making this schema up for you, so
它开始为你做这个模式，所以
it's a very different kind of way of thinking about.
这是一种非常不同的思考方式。
You don't think of it from a scheme of design point.
你不会从设计点的方案中考虑它。
In advance, there's kind of more organic as you go and
在前进的过程中，你会看到更多的有机食物
also you don't have to,
你也不必这么做，
you know, kind of create this whole scheme of front and
你知道，要创建整个前面的方案
describe it, you can describe it as you use it essentially.
描述它，你可以用它来描述它。
So it's a very interesting comparison between the two.
所以这是两个很有趣的比较。
I wish I had time to do CloudKit.
我希望我有时间做CloudKit。
Last quarter, I had the extra lectures.
上个季度，我有额外的讲座。
I was able to do CloudKit as a whole lecture but,
我做了一整节课的CloudKit，
we'll have to do it as a Friday section this week so,
我们将在这周的周五课上做，
don't miss that.
不要错过。
Next Monday is a holiday.
下星期一是假日。
So no lecture and then next Wednesday,
没有讲座，下周三，
I'm gonna go over your requirements for
我来解释一下你的要求
the final project, which are required to do.
最后的项目，需要做的。
And I'm also gonna have a lecture as well on AutoLayout.
我还会有一场关于自我介绍的讲座。
We'll finally get to Autolayout and
我们最终会到达自动降落场
how do that Autolayout stuff.
你是怎么做的?
I'd say, I just wanted to show you that and
我想说，我只是想给你们展示一下
I will see you all on Wednesday.
周三再见。
>> For more please visit us on Stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu